¬ Text file converted with loc_parser
{DRT_ROMAN_PROTECTORATE}				Accept that your independence is at an end, and become a vasall. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ALLIANCE}					An alliance between us would cause our enemies to tremble in fear. 
{DRT_ROMAN_CEASEFIRE}					It is time to bring this needless bloodshed to an end. 
{DRT_ROMAN_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}				It is time to end our alliance and for each to follow his own road to greatness! 
{DRT_ROMAN_TRADE}					Trade would bring wealth to both our peoples. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ACCESS}					The right to march our armies across your lands would greatly aid us in defeating our enemies. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ATTACK}					Your assistance against our enemies would be greatly appreciated. 
{DRT_ROMAN_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_ROMAN_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_ROMAN_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_ROMAN_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_GIFT}				A recognition of our worth is always welcome. Our thanks. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_BRIBE}				Gold always eases the chance of misunderstanding before friendship is achieved. Our thanks. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}			Your acceptance is as gracious as it is sensible. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}			Your rejection is gracious, but hardly sensible. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}			You have left us with little - that is to say, no - choice. 
{DRT_ROMAN_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}			Bandying words is a pointless waste of breath at this time. 
{DRT_ROMAN_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}			We have talked for a long time to little purpose, and yet decided nothing. This negotiation must come to an end. 
{DRT_ROMAN_REJECT_BRIBE}				Our honour and friendship are not cheap goods in a market, even for your gold. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}			Our freedom is precious, and not surrendered lightly. We see no need to become your servants - no matter how this is hidden behind fine words. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}				An alliance would not be in our best interests at this time. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}				We see no need to end the fighting between our peoples just yet. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_NULLIFY}				We can see no valid reason to end the alliance between our two peoples. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_ACCESS}				While you can see the need to march your soldiers through our lands, we do not. Permission must be refused at this time. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_REGION}				Our forefathers spent their lives to secure this land. Our blood has been spent to keep it. It is not our way to meekly hand over land to such as you!
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_ATTACK}				Attacking these people would not be in our best interests and so we must, regretfully, reject your request. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_OFFER}				This proposal is not what we expect or want. We decline your offer. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_DEMAND}				Even if you offered up your daughters as Vestals or your wives as harlots, we would not bow to your demands.
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}			We cannot give up our lands, even for your gold.
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}			In all honour, we cannot accept your proposition, lest we be seen as thieves!
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}			In all honour, we cannot accept your offer. We are willing to talk, not prostitute ourselves for a pittance.
{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}			We accept your well-intentioned and magnanimous proposition. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_COUNTER}				Your response to our proposal is acceptable. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_ROMAN_COUNTER_OFFER}				We propose the following...
{DRT_ROMAN_COUNTER_DEMAND}				We suggest the following...
{DRT_ROMAN_COUNTER_INFO}				We trust you will find this information useful...
{DRT_ROMAN_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}			After considering your proposal, we feel this proposal would more truly serve our interests...
{DRT_ROMAN_COUNTER_BRIBE}				Our good will could be secured, I'm sure, through a suitable golden gift...
{DRT_ROMAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}			Welcome, Friend! What do you need to talk about?
{DRT_ROMAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}			Greetings! What do you wish to propose?
{DRT_ROMAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}			Make this quick! War leaves little time for niceties towards the likes of you!
{DRT_ROMAN_FINISHED}					This negotiation must end. May God bless our next meeting so that it is as useful as this one! 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_PROTECTORATE}				Accept that your time of independence is now over. You are most likely to live long under our protection as vasall. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ALLIANCE}				An alliance between us would cause all our enemies to tremble in terror. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_CEASEFIRE}				It is time to end the bloodshed. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}			It is time to end for us to be honest and plain. Let us put aside words of friendship such as "alliance" and go our separate ways. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_TRADE}					Trade between our peoples would bring much wealth to all of us.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCESS}					The right to pursue our enemies across your lands would greatly help us.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ATTACK}					Your assistance against our enemies would be a great thing, and earn our thanks. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_GIFT}				A gift is the blessing to the giver. Our thanks. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_BRIBE}				Gold always helps avoid misunderstanding between those who would be friends. Many thanks.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}		Your acceptance shows strength of character as well as wisdom. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}			Your rejection is poorly considered, and could be taken as an insult by less understanding people. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}		You have left us with no choice.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}			Bandying empty words with such as you is a waste of time just now. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}		We have done you the honour of listening to your tripe, and yet nothing has been said here that was worth the hearing. This babbling is over.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_REJECT_BRIBE}				We are not simple-minded. Our honour and friendship are not cheap goods for sale in a market. No, not even for your gold. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}			Freedom is a precious thing, and not given up lightly. You do not need us as your servants and slaves. Your fine words have not hidden the truth of what you say. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}			An alliance would not be a good thing. We have spoken, and will not change our minds. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}			End the fighting! This is a good joke! We see no need to end the fighting between our peoples just yet. Some of you yet live! 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_NULLIFY}				We do not agree. We can see no excuse that would mean the end of our alliance. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_ACCESS}				While you can see the need to march your soldiers through our lands, we cannot. We are not yet simpletons, and so refuse. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_REGION}				The barrows and tombs of our forefathers are here. Our blood has been spilled over this land. We cannot give you any part of our birthright! 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_ATTACK}				We cannot see how an attack on these people would help us and so we must, regretfully, reject your demand. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_OFFER}				This offer is not what we hoped or expected, and we must turn you down. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_DEMAND}				Even if you offered up your daughters as Vestals or your wives as harlots, we would not bow to your demands.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}			We cannot give up our lands, even for such trinkets.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}		Your offer is generous, very generous - and for that reason we must turn it down. We will not be known as thieves!
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}		You must take us for simple-minded fools who cannot count. We cannot accept such paltry terms.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}			We accept your well-intentioned and generous offer.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_COUNTER}				Your answer is acceptable.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_COUNTER_OFFER}				We offer...
{DRT_BARBARIAN_COUNTER_DEMAND}			We suggest the following...
{DRT_BARBARIAN_COUNTER_INFO}				We hope you will find this useful...
{DRT_BARBARIAN_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}			After talking it over, we think this is better...
{DRT_BARBARIAN_COUNTER_BRIBE}				Our friendship could be made certain, I'm sure, through a suitably large tribute - 'gift' would be a better word, perhaps - of gold...
{DRT_BARBARIAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}		Welcome friend! How can we help you?
{DRT_BARBARIAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}		Greetings! What did you wish to offer us today?
{DRT_BARBARIAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}		Be quick. There are better things to do today than listen to your pathetic mewling! 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_FINISHED}				This talk is over. May our next meeting be as useful...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_PROTECTORATE}				It is time to accept that your independence is at an end, and become a vasall protected by our might and cushioned by our wealth. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ALLIANCE}					An alliance between us could cause our enemies much fear, and this would be good. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_CEASEFIRE}				It is time to bring this profitless war to an end. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}				It is time to end our profitless alliance...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_TRADE}					Trade between our peoples would bring much wealth, and in wealth lies greatness.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCESS}					Being allowed to march across your lands would greatly benefit us in our struggles against many enemies.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ATTACK}					Your assistance against our enemies would be greatly appreciated.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_GIFT}				A gift is always welcome, and reflects well upon the giver. Our gratitude for your kindness. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_BRIBE}				Gold can always ease any burden that friendship would impose. Our gratitude is almost boundless. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}		Your acceptance is profitable to all, and a sign that wisdom has not died amongst your people. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}			Your refusal is gracious, but perhaps ill-considered.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}		You have left us with no choice but accept your decision.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}			Platitudes and empty words from such as you are pointless distractions at this time.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}		Our ears grow weary of your endless chatter. Nothing worthy has been said. Good day.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_REJECT_BRIBE}				Our honour, loyalty and friendship are not cheap trinkets, to be purchased for a handful of coins. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}			Our freedom is precious, and not surrendered lightly. We see no need to become your servants - no matter how this is hidden behind fine words. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}				An alliance would not be in our best interests at this time.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}			We see no need to end the fighting between our peoples at the moment.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_NULLIFY}				We can see cause why the alliance between us should come to an end.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_ACCESS}				We cannot understand your need to march troops through our lands. This cannot happen. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_REGION}				This ground is ours, bought and paid for in the blood of many good and noble men. We will not grant dominion to you. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_ATTACK}				Attacking these people be neither profitable or wise for us, so we must refuse your request. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_OFFER}				This offer is not what we expected. We refuse it.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_DEMAND}				We cannot agree to this, even if you offered up your children and your children's children to be our slaves.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}			We cannot give up our lands, not even for all the treasure you offer.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}		A wise trader offers correct value: offer too much, and suspicions are raised. We must reject your offer.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}		A wise trader knows the value of what he seeks. Your valuation is cheap not wise, and we reject your offer.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}			We accept your magnanimous offer.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_COUNTER}				Your response to our generous proposal is welcome.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_COUNTER_OFFER}				We propose the following...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_COUNTER_DEMAND}				We suggest the following...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_COUNTER_INFO}				We trust you will find this information useful...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}			After considering your proposal, we feel this would be more profitable to all our interests...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_COUNTER_BRIBE}				Our friendship could be secured through a suitably large gift of gold...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}		Welcome friend and ally! How can we help you?
{DRT_CARTHAGE_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}		Greetings! What do you wish to propose?
{DRT_CARTHAGE_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}		Be quick, as our patience is not limitless, nor our kindness always guaranteed! 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_FINISHED}					This negotiation is over. May our next meeting be as fruitful...
{DRT_GREEK_PROTECTORATE}				Accept that your illusory independence is at an end. A future as a vasall under our protection is your destiny. 
{DRT_GREEK_ALLIANCE}					An alliance between us would cause all our enemies to tremble in terror. 
{DRT_GREEK_CEASEFIRE}					It is time to end the bloodshed. 
{DRT_GREEK_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}				Everything has a time to live and a time to die. Our alliance has reached its time to die, so let us part respectfully. 
{DRT_GREEK_TRADE}					Trade would bring much wealth to all our people. 
{DRT_GREEK_ACCESS}					Allowing us to march across your lands to attack our foes would be an act of true friendship. 
{DRT_GREEK_ATTACK}					Your assistance against our enemies would be greatly appreciated.
{DRT_GREEK_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_GREEK_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_GREEK_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_GREEK_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_GIFT}					A gift - once properly assessed and valued - is always welcome. Our thanks to you. 
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_BRIBE}				Gold is the surest paving on the path to mutual friendship. Many thanks. 
{DRT_GREEK_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}			Your acceptance is gracious, wise and rational. 
{DRT_GREEK_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}			Your rejection is gracious, but poorly considered.
{DRT_GREEK_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}			You have left us with no choice.
{DRT_GREEK_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}			Your words are as empty as your sophistries and mock-philosophies. We are not inclined to listen any longer. 
{DRT_GREEK_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}			We cannot listen to further nonsense. You have talked and talked and talked, and yet said almost nothing. 
{DRT_GREEK_REJECT_BRIBE}				Our honour and friendship are not for sale. Negotiation is one thing; insults, now, are something else entirely. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}			Our freedom is precious, and not given up easily. We see no need to become your bondsmen and slaves - no matter how this is rationalised. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}				An alliance would not be to our benefit just at the moment. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}				An end to the war? Perhaps, in the fullness of time. But we see no reason to end the fighting just yet. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_NULLIFY}				We can see no rational excuse to end our alliance now. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_ACCESS}				While it makes sense to you to march troops through our lands, it is unnecessary. With all due respect, our permission to do this must be withheld. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_REGION}				Our forefather's blood watered the ground here. Our people have worked these fields. We cannot meekly hand over any part of our land to you! 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_ATTACK}				Attacking these people would not be in our interests and so we must, regretfully, reject your request.
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_OFFER}				This proposal is not what we wanted. We refuse to agree to your scheme. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_DEMAND}				Even if you could show us miracles to support your arguments, we would not bow the knee to your demands. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}			We cannot give up land, not even - perhaps especially - for gold. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}			You offer too much, and in good conscience we cannot accept.
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}			Your offer is neither fair nor reasonable. We cannot accept something so paltry.
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}				We accept your offer. It is generous and fair. 
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_COUNTER}				Your response to our proposal is rational and clear-thinking. Our thanks.  
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_GREEK_COUNTER_OFFER}				We suggest the following...
{DRT_GREEK_COUNTER_DEMAND}				We ask for the following...
{DRT_GREEK_COUNTER_INFO}				We trust you will find this information useful...
{DRT_GREEK_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}			After considering your proposal, we feel the following would be to our benefit... 
{DRT_GREEK_COUNTER_BRIBE}				Anyone who wished to demonstrate true friendship could always offer a suitable gift of gold...
{DRT_GREEK_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}			Welcome, noble ally! How may we help you?
{DRT_GREEK_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}			Greetings to you! What did you wish to propose?
{DRT_GREEK_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}			Greetings, honourable foe! What did you wish to discuss before your untimely end? 
{DRT_GREEK_FINISHED}					This negotiation must end. May our next encounter be as useful...
{DRT_EGYPT_PROTECTORATE}				Accept that your time of independence is now over. You are mostly likely to live long and prosper under our Khan`s protection. 
{DRT_EGYPT_ALLIANCE}					An alliance may cause Khan's enemies to tremble in fear. This would be a fine thing. 
{DRT_EGYPT_CEASEFIRE}					Khan considers that the time is right to end the bloodshed that taints our relationship. 
{DRT_EGYPT_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}				Khan feels that it is time to end the alliance with you. 
{DRT_EGYPT_TRADE}					Khan recognises that trade would do much to bring wealth to his servants and children. 
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCESS}					Khan considers that asking permission to march across your territory before he exercises his divine right to do so avoids confusion and makes you feel better. 
{DRT_EGYPT_ATTACK}					Your humble assistance against the great Khan's enemies would be greatly appreciated.
{DRT_EGYPT_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_EGYPT_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EGYPT_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_EGYPT_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_GIFT}				A gift is a blessing to the giver. May Khan's thanks warm your souls. 
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_BRIBE}				Gold can often aid in easing misunderstanding between those who would be friends. 
{DRT_EGYPT_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}			Your acceptance is as gracious as it is wise.
{DRT_EGYPT_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}			Your rejection is not gracious, and likely to cause much offence to our noble Khan. 
{DRT_EGYPT_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}			You have left the Khan with no choice in this matter.
{DRT_EGYPT_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}			Bandying empty words with such as you is a pointless distraction from the proper business of state.
{DRT_EGYPT_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}			Many words have been spoken, and have blown away as on the desert wind. Nothing worthy of Khan's attention has been spoken and this negotiation is ended.
{DRT_EGYPT_REJECT_BRIBE}				Khan's honour and friendship are not for sale, particularly for such a derisory sum in gold. 
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}			Khan's rule is precious, and not surrendered lightly. He sees no need to become your servant - no matter how this is concealed by smooth words. 
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}				An alliance would not be in Khan's interest at this time.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}				The wise and belligerent Khan sees no reason to stop fighting just yet.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_NULLIFY}				The wise and faithful Khan sees no excuse to dishonour himself and his friends by denying that a mutual friendship continues to exist. 
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_ACCESS}				While you may see a reason to march your troops through Khan's lands, he does not. Permission is refused. 
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_REGION}				All that is good is here, all that our forefathers' worked to achieve. Khan cannot, in all conscience, hand over a land held in sacred trust from the Gods.  
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_ATTACK}				In what way would the peace-loving and kindly Khan profit from such an attack? Your request is objectionable.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_OFFER}				This proposal is not what Khan expects from supplicants, and it is declined.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_DEMAND}				Even if you offered up your children as slaves to the greater glory of Khan, he would not consider bowing to your demands.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}			We cannot give up our lands, even for inadequate amounts of gold.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}			Khan wonders if you understand the process of negotiation. Your offer is so embarrassingly high that we cannot accept it.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}			Khan would consider your offer too worthless to be worthy of acceptance.
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}				The magnanimous Khan has smiled upon your well-crafted proposal.
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_COUNTER}				Your response to Khan's proposal is acceptable, if a little tardy...
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_EGYPT_COUNTER_OFFER}				In the name of Khan, we propose the following...
{DRT_EGYPT_COUNTER_DEMAND}				In the name of Khan, we suggest the following compromise...
{DRT_EGYPT_COUNTER_INFO}				In the name of Khan, we trust you will find this information useful...
{DRT_EGYPT_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}			After due consideration the mighty Khan feels this would more truly serve his interests...
{DRT_EGYPT_COUNTER_BRIBE}				Khan's friendship would be facilitated by a suitably large tribute in gold. Perhaps, on reflection, it might be better to term it a gift. Yes, gift...
{DRT_EGYPT_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}			Welcome, friend of the great Khan! What aid do you require?
{DRT_EGYPT_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}			Greetings from the noble and magnificent Khan. What proposal or do you wish to lay, most humbly, before him?
{DRT_EGYPT_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}			Be speedy, for Khan's servants have many matter of state that take precedence over such as you. 
{DRT_EGYPT_FINISHED}					This negotiation must now end. May the next meeting be as useful...
{DRT_EASTERN_PROTECTORATE}				Accept the reality of your situation and, with good grace, accept that you need protection in this dangerous world. It is time to become our vasall.
{DRT_EASTERN_ALLIANCE}					In truth, an alliance between us would bring fear to the hearts of all our enemies.
{DRT_EASTERN_CEASEFIRE}					It is time for all bloodshed to end. Let us cease our struggles. 
{DRT_EASTERN_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}				The time is ripe to re-evaluate our alliance and bring it to a peaceful conclusion, but a conclusion nonetheless. 
{DRT_EASTERN_TRADE}					Trade between friends is always welcome for the wealth that it brings.  
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCESS}					We ask for the right to march our armies through your territory, so that we may strike down our foes from an unexpected direction. 
{DRT_EASTERN_ATTACK}					Assistance against our enemies would be greatly appreciated, and could only increase the respect in which you are held by our people. 
{DRT_EASTERN_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_EASTERN_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EASTERN_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_EASTERN_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_GIFT}				A gift is a blessing to the giver, no matter how small it may be. Our thanks to you. 
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_BRIBE}				Gold is the surest way to ease tensions that would otherwise cause friendship to be stillborn and sterile. Our thanks to you.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}			Your acceptance is prudent and gracious.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}			Your rejection is imprudent, but graciously done. 
{DRT_EASTERN_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}			You have left us with no choice.
{DRT_EASTERN_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}			This bandying of empty words is simply noise in the wind, not negotiation. 
{DRT_EASTERN_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}		The talking has gone on and on and on and on, and nothing has been settled. This negotiation is now ended and we are immensely relieved to be done with it all.
{DRT_EASTERN_REJECT_BRIBE}				Honour and friendship are not trade goods to be sold for a purse of gold. At least two - no, three or four - purses are considered a polite beginning... 
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}			We surrender our independence to no man. Why should we become slaves? For the sake of a few fine words? We think not! 
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}				We feel that an alliance would not be in our best interests.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}				We see little need to end the fighting just yet. Perhaps later, when you have learned the value of peace...
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_NULLIFY}				We see little need to end such a profitable and benign relationship. The alliance between us is a bulwark against jealous rivals! 
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_ACCESS}				Although you see good reasons to march your armies hither and thither through our lands, we do not. We must turn down your request.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_REGION}				Our dead lie in this ground. Our cities cover the land. Our farmers work the earth. We see no good reason to give up even the smallest part of our possessions!
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_ATTACK}				Attacking these people is not something that we could undertake lightly, so we must refuse to carry out your wishes for now. 
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_OFFER}				This proposal is not appropriate. We decline your offer.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_DEMAND}				We will not bow to your demands. Conqueror's justice is no justice at all, and this would be the first step along that road. 
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}			We cannot give up our lands, not even for gold. Not even for that much gold. 
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}		Your foolish generosity fools no one! What are you up to? We reject your offer!
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}			Your insulting parsimony would not fool a child. Why do you not make a sensible offer? We reject this proposal.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}			We accept your offer. May we both profit from this agreement.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_COUNTER}				Your response is acceptable. May we both profit from this agreement.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_EASTERN_COUNTER_OFFER}				We offer the following...
{DRT_EASTERN_COUNTER_DEMAND}				We demand the following...
{DRT_EASTERN_COUNTER_INFO}				We trust you will find this information useful...
{DRT_EASTERN_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}			After considering your last offer, we feel this arrangement would be more equitable...
{DRT_EASTERN_COUNTER_BRIBE}				Friendship can be encouraged with gold, if this is offered in suitable quantities...
{DRT_EASTERN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}			Welcome unto you, noble and generous ally! What help do you need? 
{DRT_EASTERN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}		Greetings, esteemed one! What do you wish to propose?
{DRT_EASTERN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}		What? Well, come on, what? There is no time to waste listening to anything other than the quickest of proposals...
{DRT_EASTERN_FINISHED}					These talks are ended. May our next meeting be as profitable...


¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 22/03/2004 17:30:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************


¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 21/04/2004 17:30:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 13/05/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

{DRT_BARBARIAN_PROTECTORATE}				Accept that your time of independence is now over. You will live long and prosper under our protection. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_GREEK_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_GREEK_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_GREEK_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_GREEK_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 03/06/2004 16:48:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

{DRT_ROMAN_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_ROMAN_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_ROMAN_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_ROMAN_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_EGYPT_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_EGYPT_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EGYPT_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_EGYPT_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_EASTERN_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_EASTERN_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EASTERN_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_EASTERN_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.

{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				Although your proposal is lacking in merit, we must accept it.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			We must accept this insulting proposal as, at heart, we are realists first and foremost.
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				You think to insult Khan with this proposal, but for the good of His people He will ignore your crudity.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			We must accept your proposal, although it pains us to do so.
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				We must accept this insulting proposal as, at heart, we are realists first and foremost.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			Although your proposal profits us little, we must accept it.

{DRT_EGYPT_PROTECTORATE}				Khan - health and strength to him - states: "All Your Base Are Belong To Us!" It is time to become a vasall under the kindly rule of The Great Khan. 

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 17/06/2004 13:01:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*		This particular divider does not denote a changes round.
¬*	This is when the files were locked to be sent for Russian and Polish translation.
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 01/07/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 07/07/2004 17:15:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

{DRT_ROMAN_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}	While your offer of territory is generous, we do not think we would keep it for long before your armies marched in and so we reject it. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}	What is given can soon be taken away! We must reject your offer of access, as you may simply revoke it and leave our armies stranded. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}	We are not fools. If we granted you marching rights, you would not march on your enemies. Our lands would be prey to your ambitions!
{DRT_ROMAN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}	We do not wish you to attack our rivals. We have no faith that your soldiers would ever see a battlefield and less faith that your promises are worthwhile.
{DRT_ROMAN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}	Your words promise peace, but your actions have not always been those of peaceful men. Your promise not to attack us cannot be trusted, and we reject this offer.
{DRT_ROMAN_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}	We will not take your gold. We have no faith that we would ever see the money you promise so glibly. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}	You offer us land, but we do not believe that it would be ours for long! Before another harvest is gathered, your armies will have snatched it back. We reject your offer!
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}	Your words are worthless! In one breath you will give the right to march on your lands, and with the next deny that any such words were spoken. Perhaps you look for an excuse for war...
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}	Only trusting fools would grant you the right to march armies across their lands. We are not trusting fools. You may not pass!
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}	Your word cannot be trusted. You say that you will attack our foes, but only a witless idiot would listen and believe such a thing...
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}	Your words sound sweet and would be welcome if they came from honest warriors. But too often you have said one thing and done another. We must reject your promise.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}	We will not take your gold. It is tainted with lies and false friendship, a gift made by ill-speaking liars to fools - and we are not fools! 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}	We cannot accept lands from you. The risk is too great and we would not profit by it. If we take your gift, your soldiers will only snatch it back!
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}	We would not profit by marching armies through your land. You would only change your minds afterwards. We reject this proposal.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}	We cannot give you the right to march through our lands. You may - it is true - be entirely honourable, but your history weighs heavily against you...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}	Your offer to attack our rivals may be sincere, but we prefer to think otherwise. We reject your offer as profitless and too risky to believe.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}	Too often in the past you have promised peace and then settled matters with the sword. Maybe there is profit in believing you will not attack, but we reject your offer.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}	Your words promise gold, but the glitter of your gold cannot blind us to the swords in your hands. We must reject your offer of tribute for our own safety.
{DRT_GREEK_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}	Your offer of lands sounds sincere, but your previous conduct leads us to suspect that you have already mustered an army to recapture them! We reject your offer.
{DRT_GREEK_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}	We have no intention of marching into your lands with your permission. Your words may promise much, but your actions tell a different tale.
{DRT_GREEK_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}	You demand the right to march across our lands, but only a drooling imbecile would agree to such a proposal. Too often you have turned on friends, broken promises and lied!
{DRT_GREEK_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}	We cannot trust you to do as you say, for your words have been false in the past. We reject your offer of an attack on our rivals. 
{DRT_GREEK_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}	Your promises not to attack are fine words, and would be believable in the mouths of honest men. Yet from you, they somehow sound hollow. We must reject your offer.
{DRT_GREEK_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}	Your gold is indeed a fine gift, but a gift is only as good as the giver. A tribute from you would therefore be worthless and largely dishonourable. Thus, we cast it aside.
{DRT_EGYPT_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}	The Khan rejects your offer of new lands to rule. When such as you cast a thing aside, it is hardly worthy! Besides, He believes that, in time, you would dishonourably snatch back your gift!
{DRT_EGYPT_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}	The Khan has no interest in marching his armies through your lands. After all, you may change your minds and attack His servants once they are far from home!
{DRT_EGYPT_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}	The Khan does not wish His lands to be polluted by your armies, and your request is denied. After all, you cannot be trusted to march through without attacking!
{DRT_EGYPT_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}	The Khan does not need the aid of such as you in attacking his rivals and foes. Although you may promise much, the past shows that you achieve little!
{DRT_EGYPT_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}	The Khan is not a fool, so why do you try to deceive him with false peace? Your word is known to be as worthless as the desert dust, so He must reject your hollow promises.
{DRT_EGYPT_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}	The Khan does not need your gold. The tribute of the worthless is, of itself, worthless in His sight. The Khan thusly spurns your offer.
{DRT_EASTERN_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}	Your reputation goes before you! We must reject your offer of lands to rule as our own. They would, we believe, only be ours for as long as it took you to march across them!
{DRT_EASTERN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}	We have no intention of marching into your lands! Your words say one thing, but your actions have often told a different story. Only a fool puts his hand in the lion's mouth!
{DRT_EASTERN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}	Honesty is sometimes best: we feel that giving you the right to march in our lands is the same thing as asking you to invade us! We must refuse your request.
{DRT_EASTERN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}	While your offer to attack our rivals is welcome, we doubt its sincerity and your intentions. We refuse to become involved in your schemes and plots. 
{DRT_EASTERN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}	We are not fooled by your words. We reject your new-found promises of peace and harmony. Your actions in the past have always spoken loudly of war and blood, of dishonour and death.
{DRT_EASTERN_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}	Your gold is not welcome, for we do not believe that tribute from you would be truly sincere - or even paid into our coffers, for that matter!

{DRT_ROMAN_THREAT}				Our wrath can be turned aside, providing that you are sufficiently respectful - and can afford the price...
{DRT_ROMAN_BRIBE}				PLACEHOLDER A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_ROMAN_GIFT}				Accept this gift as a mark of our admiration for your virtue and courage. 
{DRT_ROMAN_INFO}				If we share our knowledge of the world we will all benefit. 

{DRT_BARBARIAN_THREAT}				Our swords can always be turned aside by gold. But can your peace and life be valued too highly?
{DRT_BARBARIAN_BRIBE}				PLACEHOLDER A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_GIFT}				Accept this gift in a spirit of warrior brotherhood! Let us never draw swords against one another! 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_INFO}				Wisdom shared is wisdom gained, so let us share what we know of the world and both gain by it!

{DRT_CARTHAGE_THREAT}				Gold is always preferable to blood. For a price our armies will not march against you. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_BRIBE}				PLACEHOLDER A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_GIFT}				Accept this gift as more than a token of our good will. It is in an investment in our future as friends!
{DRT_CARTHAGE_INFO}				Combining our knowledge of the world will profit both of us.

{DRT_EGYPT_THREAT}				Khan's mighty wrath is not cheaply turned aside! His mighty armies will not attack, but only for the right price.
{DRT_EGYPT_BRIBE}				PLACEHOLDER A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EGYPT_GIFT}				Khan is pleased to offer even unworthy mortals such as yourselves gifts and trinkets as signs of his good will. 
{DRT_EGYPT_INFO}				Khan's knowledge is boundless, but combining it with your paltry knowledge of the world will surely benefit us all.

{DRT_EASTERN_THREAT}				There may be enough gold in your coffers to run aside our armies. You must consider the value of your lives and freedom...
{DRT_EASTERN_BRIBE}				PLACEHOLDER A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EASTERN_GIFT}				The gift is a blessing to the giver. In that spirit, accept this humble offering of ours...
{DRT_EASTERN_INFO}				Wisdom shared is wisdom gained, so let us share what we know of the world and profit by it!

{DRT_GREEK_THREAT}				Our honour is not for sale. But our swords can be kept sheathed for a price... a good price.
{DRT_GREEK_BRIBE}				PLACEHOLDER A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_GREEK_GIFT}				Our gifts do much honour to the recipients. Accept these offerings in a spirit of brotherhood!
{DRT_GREEK_INFO}				Wisdom shared is wisdom doubled, so let us all profit from the sharing of knowledge!


{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			Although your proposal is lacking in merit, honour and virtue, we must accept it.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}		We must accept this insulting proposal because we have no alternative, but do not expect us to smile and celebrate.
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			Khan will rise above your slurs on His honour and accept this crude and insulting proposal, but only for the good of His people.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}		Sometimes the strong warrior must bite his tongue and accept the unacceptable. We agree to your proposal, for now...
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			Your proposal would shame a helot, but we must accept it. We will not thank  God for their help in this matter...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}		Your proposal has little profit in it, and less to like. Even so, we must accept your offer. 

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 15/07/2004 17:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 22/07/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 29/07/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 05/08/2004 12:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 12/08/2004 09:53:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 19/08/2004 16:05:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

{DRT_EASTERN_THREAT}	There may be enough gold in your coffers to turn aside our armies. You must consider the value of your lives and freedom...

{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_OFFER}	This offer cannot be matched. We must decline your offer. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_OFFER}	We having nothing to offer in return, and we must turn you down. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_OFFER}	We cannot meet this offer and therefore must refuse it.
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_OFFER}	We must decline. We cannot offer anything in return. 
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_OFFER}	This proposal is beyond our means, we must regretfully decline.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_OFFER}	We cannot equal this proposition and must turn it down.

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 01/09/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 03/09/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

{DRT_ROMAN_BRIBE}				A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_BRIBE}				A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_BRIBE}				A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EGYPT_BRIBE}				A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EASTERN_BRIBE}				A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_GREEK_BRIBE}				A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.


¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			EXPANSION PACK TEXT BEGINS HERE!!!
¬*		ALL TEXT BELOW THIS LINE SHOULD BE EXPANSION ADDITIONS/CHANGES ONLY!!!
¬*
¬*¬***** Changes made after 05/01/2005 15:18:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++


¬ Typo corrected	
{DRT_BARBARIAN_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}		It is time to be honest and plain. Let us put aside words of friendship such as "alliance" and go our separate ways. 

¬ Hun and Nomad variants	

{DRT_HUN_ACCEPT_BRIBE}				Gold always smooths the path to understanding between those who would be friends. Many thanks.
{DRT_HUN_ACCEPT_COUNTER}			Your answer is acceptable.
{DRT_HUN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			Sometimes the strong warrior must bite his tongue and accept the unacceptable. We agree to your proposal, for now...
{DRT_HUN_ACCEPT_GIFT}				A gift is a measure of the giver. Our thanks. 
{DRT_HUN_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}			We accept your well-intentioned and generous offer.
{DRT_HUN_ACCESS}				The right to pursue our enemies across your lands would greatly help us.
{DRT_HUN_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}		Your acceptance shows wisdom.
{DRT_HUN_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}		You have left us with no choice.
{DRT_HUN_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}		Your rejection is poorly considered, and could be taken as an insult by some. 
{DRT_HUN_ALLIANCE}				An alliance between us would cause all our enemies to tremble in terror. 
{DRT_HUN_ATTACK}				Your assistance against our enemies would earn our goodwill.
{DRT_HUN_BRIBE}				A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_HUN_CEASEFIRE}				It is time to end the bloodshed. 
{DRT_HUN_COUNTER_BRIBE}			Our friendship could be made certain through a suitably large tribute - perhaps 'gift' would be a better word - of gold...
{DRT_HUN_COUNTER_DEMAND}			We suggest the following...
{DRT_HUN_COUNTER_INFO}				We hope you will find this useful...
{DRT_HUN_COUNTER_OFFER}			We offer...
{DRT_HUN_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}			After mulling over your proposal we think that this is better...
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_ACCESS}			While you can see the need to send your warriors through our lands, we cannot. We must refuse, in case others think we are simpletons.
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}			An alliance would not be a good thing. We have spoken, and will not change our minds. 
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_ATTACK}			We cannot see how an attack on these people would help us. We must reject your demand. 
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}			End the fighting! This is a good joke! We see no need to end any fighting. Some of you yet live!
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_DEMAND}			Even if you offered up your entrails on the altars of our highest gods, we would not consider listening to such demands. 
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_NULLIFY}			We do not agree. We can see no excuse that would mean the end of our alliance. 
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_OFFER}			We having nothing to offer in return, and we must turn you down. 
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}		Your offer is generous, very generous - and for that reason we must turn it down. The sharpest sword can be hidden beneath a pile of gold…
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}		You must take us for simple-minded fools who cannot count. We cannot accept such paltry terms.
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}		Freedom is a precious thing, and not given up lightly. You do not need us as your servants and slaves. Your fine words are just that - words on the wind.
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_REGION}			Our blood has been spilled over this land. Our dead lie here. We have bought this land with lives. We cannot give you any part of our birthright! 
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_THREAT}			Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}		We cannot give up our lands, even for such trinkets.
{DRT_HUN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}		Only trusting fools would grant you the right to send armies across their lands. We are not trusting fools. You may not pass!
{DRT_HUN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}		Your words are worthless! In one breath you will give the right to pass across your lands, and with the next deny that any such words were spoken. Perhaps you look for an excuse for war…
{DRT_HUN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}		Your word cannot be trusted. You say that you will attack our foes, but only a witless idiot would listen and believe such a thing...
{DRT_HUN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}		Your words would be welcome from honest warriors, but too often you have said one thing and done another. We must reject your promise.
{DRT_HUN_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}		You offer us land, but we do not believe that it would be ours for long! Before the foals are born, your armies will have snatched it back. We reject your offer!
{DRT_HUN_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}		We will not take your gold. It is tainted with lies and false friendship, a gift made by ill-speaking liars to fools - and we are not fools! 
{DRT_HUN_FINISHED}				This talk is over. May our next meeting be as useful...
{DRT_HUN_GIFT}					Accept this gift in a spirit of warrior brotherhood! Let us never draw swords against one another! 
{DRT_HUN_INFO}					Wisdom shared is wisdom gained, so let us share what we know of the world!
{DRT_HUN_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}			It is time to be honest and plain. Let us put aside words of friendship such as "alliance" and go our separate ways. 
{DRT_HUN_PROTECTORATE}			Accept that your time of freedom is now over. You will live long and prosper under our protection. 
{DRT_HUN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}		Welcome friend! How can we help you?
{DRT_HUN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}		Be quick. There are better things to do today than listen to your pathetic mewling! 
{DRT_HUN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}		Greetings! What did you wish to offer us today?
{DRT_HUN_REJECT_BRIBE}				We are not simple-minded. Our honour and friendship are not cheap goods for sale in a market. No, not even for your gold. 
{DRT_HUN_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}		Bandying empty words with such as you is a waste of time just now. 
{DRT_HUN_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}		We have done you the honour of listening to your tripe, and yet nothing has been said here that was worth the hearing. This babbling is over.
{DRT_HUN_THREAT}				Our swords can always be turned aside by gold. But can your peace and life be valued too highly?
{DRT_HUN_TRADE}				Trade between our peoples would bring much wealth to all of us.
{DRT_NOMAD_ACCEPT_BRIBE}			Gold always smooths the path to understanding between those who would be friends. Many thanks.
{DRT_NOMAD_ACCEPT_COUNTER}			Your answer is acceptable.
{DRT_NOMAD_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}		Sometimes the strong warrior must bite his tongue and accept the unacceptable. We agree to your proposal, for now...
{DRT_NOMAD_ACCEPT_GIFT}			A gift is a measure of the giver. Our thanks. 
{DRT_NOMAD_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}		We accept your well-intentioned and generous offer.
{DRT_NOMAD_ACCESS}				The right to pursue our enemies across your lands would greatly help us.
{DRT_NOMAD_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}		Your acceptance shows wisdom.
{DRT_NOMAD_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}		You have left us with no choice.
{DRT_NOMAD_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}		Your rejection is poorly considered, and could be taken as an insult by some. 
{DRT_NOMAD_ALLIANCE}				An alliance between us would cause all our enemies to tremble in terror. 
{DRT_NOMAD_ATTACK}				Your assistance against our enemies would earn our goodwill.
{DRT_NOMAD_BRIBE}				A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_NOMAD_CEASEFIRE}				It is time to end the bloodshed. 
{DRT_NOMAD_COUNTER_BRIBE}			Our friendship could be made certain through a suitably large tribute - perhaps 'gift' would be a better word - of gold...
{DRT_NOMAD_COUNTER_DEMAND}			We suggest the following...
{DRT_NOMAD_COUNTER_INFO}			We hope you will find this useful...
{DRT_NOMAD_COUNTER_OFFER}			We offer...
{DRT_NOMAD_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}		After mulling over your proposal we think that this is better...
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_ACCESS}			While you can see the need to send your warriors through our lands, we cannot. We must refuse, in case others think we are simpletons.
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}			An alliance would not be a good thing. We have spoken, and will not change our minds. 
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_ATTACK}			We cannot see how an attack on these people would help us. We must reject your demand. 
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}			End the fighting! This is a good joke! We see no need to end any fighting. Some of you yet live!
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_DEMAND}			Even if you offered up your entrails on the altars of our highest gods, we would not consider listening to such demands. 
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_GIFT}			Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_NULLIFY}			We do not agree. We can see no excuse that would mean the end of our alliance. 
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_OFFER}			We having nothing to offer in return, and we must turn you down. 
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}		Your offer is generous, very generous - and for that reason we must turn it down. The sharpest sword can be hidden beneath a pile of gold…
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}		You must take us for simple-minded fools who cannot count. We cannot accept such paltry terms.
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}		Freedom is a precious thing, and not given up lightly. You do not need us as your servants and slaves. Your fine words are just that - words on the wind.
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_REGION}			Our blood has been spilled over this land. Our dead lie here. We have bought this land with lives. We cannot give you any part of our birthright! 
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_THREAT}			Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}		We cannot give up our lands, even for such trinkets.
{DRT_NOMAD_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}		Only trusting fools would grant you the right to send armies across their lands. We are not trusting fools. You may not pass!
{DRT_NOMAD_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}		Your words are worthless! In one breath you will give the right to pass across your lands, and with the next deny that any such words were spoken. Perhaps you look for an excuse for war…
{DRT_NOMAD_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}		Your word cannot be trusted. You say that you will attack our foes, but only a witless idiot would listen and believe such a thing...
{DRT_NOMAD_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}		Your words would be welcome from honest warriors, but too often you have said one thing and done another. We must reject your promise.
{DRT_NOMAD_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}		You offer us land, but we do not believe that it would be ours for long! Before the foals are born, your armies will have snatched it back. We reject your offer!
{DRT_NOMAD_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}		We will not take your gold. It is tainted with lies and false friendship, a gift made by ill-speaking liars to fools - and we are not fools! 
{DRT_NOMAD_FINISHED}				This talk is over. May our next meeting be as useful...
{DRT_NOMAD_GIFT}				Accept this gift in a spirit of warrior brotherhood! Let us never draw swords against one another! 
{DRT_NOMAD_INFO}				Wisdom shared is wisdom gained, so let us share what we know of the world!
{DRT_NOMAD_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}			It is time to be honest and plain. Let us put aside words of friendship such as "alliance" and go our separate ways. 
{DRT_NOMAD_PROTECTORATE}			Accept that your time of freedom is now over. You will live long and prosper under our protection. 
{DRT_NOMAD_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}		Welcome friend! How can we help you?
{DRT_NOMAD_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}		Be quick. There are better things to do today than listen to your pathetic mewling! 
{DRT_NOMAD_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}	Greetings! What did you wish to offer us today?
{DRT_NOMAD_REJECT_BRIBE}			We are not simple-minded. Our honour and friendship are not cheap goods for sale in a market. No, not even for your gold. 
{DRT_NOMAD_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}		Bandying empty words with such as you is a waste of time just now. 
{DRT_NOMAD_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}	We have done you the honour of listening to your tripe, and yet nothing has been said here that was worth the hearing. This babbling is over.
{DRT_NOMAD_THREAT}				Our swords can always be turned aside by gold. But can your peace and life be valued too highly?
{DRT_NOMAD_TRADE}				Trade between our peoples would bring much wealth to all of us.

¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 18/04/2005 12:45:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++

¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 27/06/2005 11:50:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++

¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 08/07/2005 17:41:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++


¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 20/07/2005 12:23:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++

¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THERE SHOULD NOW BE NO MORE CHANGES! 
¬*			SEE ROSS/LUCI/MIKE!
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 05/08/2005 16:25:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++