¬ Text used for building names and descriptions
¬ Lines that begin with this character are comments
¬ and should not be translated or altered
¬ Items inside curly brackets are tags and should not be translated
¬ The text following each tag on the same, or next line does need to be translated
¬

{hetaireia}
Hetaireia

{hetaireia_descr}
The Hetaireia are professional soldiers in the employ of either the emperor himself or one of his strategoi or doukes. Though excellent pay, professional soldiers are always in short supply. So the Empire uses to recruite them where ever it finds able soldiers to serve in the Imperial army. Unlike mercenaries recruited for a specific campaigne the Hetaireia are part of the regular army but weren't usually considered to be part of the Imperial Tagmata.   

{hetaireia_descr_short}
Excellent heavy cavalry with almost irresistible charge. Professional armoured lancers. Emperor's and general's bodyguard.

¬----------------

{klibanophoroi}
Klibanophoroi

{klibanophoroi_descr}
The Kataphraktoi are the Roman heavy cavalry. Though not introduced by Nikephoros II Phokas, he perfected their tactical usuage for the past century. Armoured with a klibanion sandwiched between two padded protective garments (the kabadion and epilorikion), heavy helmets,lamination, greaves, mail pieces and armed with iron maces the Kataphraktoi are an almost invulnarable.   

Though armed and trained with lance, bow, sword and mace alike, the mace was used as the nain impact weapon of the Kataphraktoi. In order to deal with enemy cavalry the Kataphraktoi fight in the way of the ancient clibanarii with lances. Nowaday we know those cataphracts as Klibanophoroi.  

{klibanophoroi_descr_short}
Very heavily armoured and disciplined cavalry. Carry lances and iron maces to make short work of enemy cavalry.

¬----------------

{kataphraktoi}
Kataphraktoi

{kataphraktoi_descr}
The Kataphraktoi are the Roman heavy cavalry. Though not introduced by Nikephoros II Phokas, he perfected their tactical usuage for the past century. Armoured with a klibanion sandwiched between two padded protective garments (the kabadion and epilorikion), heavy helmets,lamination, greaves, mail pieces and armed with iron maces the Kataphraktoi are an almost invulnarable.   

Historicly classic Kataphraktoi - though armed and trained with lance, bow, sword and mace alike - used the mace their maces as main impact weapon.

{kataphraktoi_descr_short}
Very heavily armoured and disciplined cavalry. Shock force designed to break through the enemy battle line using armour piercing maces in close combat.

¬----------------

{peltastai_enoplioi}
Kontaratoi

{peltastai_enoplioi_descr}
Since about the start of the 10th century, heavy armed infantrymen used to be armed with a long spear called kontarion makron or sarissa. Inspired by western fighting technics and by absorbing larger numbers of second rate troops and western pronoiars in original predominantly native heavy infantry, the shorter kontarion mikron or dory became more and more common even in picked units.

{peltastai_enoplioi_descr_short}
Reliable heavy battle line spearmen. Effective against cavalry and light or medium infantry.

¬----------------

{phylakes}
Kastrophylakes

{phylakes_descr}
The number of garrison soldiers needed in a kastron was minimized by employing paramilitary guards for the duties not requiring the services of a trained soldier. Thus there was a distinction between the military service performed by garrison troops and the paramilitary guard service performed by men who were not soldiers but guards, watchmen, and police. Depending on a town's size, location, and level of social organization, this guard service was undertaken either by members of the entire population or by a more or less professional group of men who regularly carried out the requisite duties.

{phylakes_descr_short}
Paramilitary watch & police forces with poor morale and low combat value. These watchmen shouldn't be expected to hold a battle line. 

¬----------------

{menavlatoi}
Menavlatoi

{menavlatoi_descr}
Menavlatoi are primary designed to serves as some sort of 'living caltrop' against enemy heavy cavalry. They generally use their heavy menavlia to stab to death armoured horses from below. Due to their shorter weapon - compared to the long spears of the Hoplitai or Skoutatoi - they can act far more flexible on the battle field. When needed they run to an other side of the formation to support an endangered sector or even skirmish alongside lighter troops.  

{menavlatoi_descr_short}
Heavy polearm troops. Thanks to their armour piercing weapon very effective against cavalry and infantry in close combat.

¬----------------

{paramonai}
Paramonai

{paramonai_descr}
The Paramonai replaced the Spatharioi as personal retainers of the doukes, strategoi & other nobles. Though not as heavy armoured as their collegues in the middle Byzantine periode they are still highly effective. Armed with mail shirt, large shield, javelins, sword or paramenion they are far more flexible than Spatharioi, Skoutatoi or Hoplitai.

{paramonai_descr_short}
Disciplined and feared heavy elite infantry. Capable of throwing spears at approaching enemies. Effective against spearmen, but not against heavy cavalry.

¬----------------

{psiloi}
Psiloi

{psiloi_descr}
Psiloi as the ancient called them are light bow-armed infantrymen. Though rated as light troops, they are well trained for both archery and melee. Like most of the native forces the Psiloi are recruited from the same feudal stock as their collegues in the heavy infantry. In fact its his superior ability with the bow that earned his place in the ranks of the Psiloi.

{psiloi_descr_short}
Profident medium line archers. Capable of fighting with both bow and sword. 

¬----------------

{riptaristai}
Riptaristai

{riptaristai_descr}
In fine Greek tradition, the Byzantine Empire fields a group of javelin wielding skirmishers. These men are drawn from the poorer themes, only wearing a tunic and trousers. They carry a small wicker or leather shield, a few javelins, and a small axe. Their javelins bring a deadly sting, and since most armies no longer use the javelin (mainly due to lack of training in its use), Riptaristai can bring a needed close support element to Roman arms. Historically, the Riptaristai were a throwback to the ancient Greek Akontistai. They were mainly hired Rhos and Slaves, but many became quite accomplished and they were all certainly valued by their Greek overlords. This was a type of infantry that saw action right up until the end of the Empire, though many times they were on the rebellious end of things...

{riptaristai_descr_short}
Light infantry with short ranged missiles, excellent at harassing enemy skirmishers or luring enemy infantry into the battle. However they suffer from weak defence and should avoid cavalry at all cost.

¬----------------

{skoutatoi}
Skoutatoi

{skoutatoi_descr}
Hoplitai, Skoutatoi or Skoutaratoi (shieldbearers) are the Roman heavily armed infantry. Armed with both sword and kontarion makron - a spear about twice as long as normal - and large shield, their main task is to provide a save heaven and place to really for the cavalry. Though most heavily armed infantry wear a padded protective garment for protection only some of the wealthier wear mail shirts, scale armour or even klibanion. Heavily armed infantry form about 50% of the battle line infantry.  

{skoutatoi_descr_short}
Reliable armoured front line spearmen. Effective against cavalry and even heavy infantry.

¬----------------

{spatharioi}
Spatharioi

{spatharioi_descr}
Each douke has a picked force of native heavy infantry - the Spatharioi. Though like most other native troopes trained with all weapons, they usually perform as sword-bearing personal bodyguards for their master. Armoured with the best available armour they provide a superb heavy infantry equal to the finest western men-at-arms.   

{spatharioi_descr_short}
Heavy swordsmen, effective even against heavy infantry but should avoid heavy cavalry. 

¬----------------

{mourtatoi}
Mourtatoi

{mourtatoi_descr}
The Empire always attracted foreigners to serve in its armies. The Mourtatoi or Murtati are renegate Turks serving as medium archers for their Christian masters. Unlike the mounted Turkopouloi the Mourtatoi didn't necessarily converted to Christendom. They can be found in both the Imperial army and in personal retunues of powerful magnates.

{mourtatoi_descr_short}
Medium archers, suited well for keeping enemy horse archers or other skirmishers at bay and capable of fighting light infantry in melee.

¬----------------

{tassinarioi}
Tassinarioi

{tassinarioi_descr}
Tassinarioi are among the finest light cavalry in the world. Drawn from Armenians settled in the frontier Thema in the east, they are familiar with raiding and guerrillia warfare. Though their loyalty to the empire and their reliabillity were put in question, they proofed highly effective against foreign raids and incursions. Tassinarioi are armoured in only a hard leather cuirass and metal helmet and greaves. They carry a saber, javelin and spear, but their true advantage lies in what their name implies. This light cavalry is capable of truly acrobatic feats upon the battlefield, often able to ride down and kill horse archers before they do significant damage. They are proficient at everything from dodging arrows to leaping upon other horses. Their main use is a fast moving guerilla and recon force, but when they fight pitched battles, they often chase horse archers down with an emotion approaching glee. Historically, the Tassinarioi were the elite leading the Thematic cavalry on their constant raids from small unit actions up to major battles. They were hired from the frontiers for their ability as horsemen, but had the Roman sense of discipline instilled from their harsh training by former members of their unit. Use them wisely, for when they are spent, apart from them the empire has no defense other than its unmounted missle units against the huge amounts of eastern mounted archers.

{tassinarioi_descr_short}
Light cavalry with strong charge. Good at chasing down archers and horse archers or flanking all but the heaviest of enemy units.

¬----------------

{toxotai}
Dismounted Toxotai

{toxotai_descr}
Though the Empire has an excellent foot archer corps, it is sometimes required for Hippo-Toxotai to dismount and to fight alongside the Psiloi as Toxotai on foot. In the Roman army dismounted cavalrymen are usually far heavier armoured than the ordinary infantry and are even more suited to fight in hand-to-hand combat. 

{toxotai_descr_short}
Dismounted Hippo-Toxotai and similar heavy armoured foot archers, suited well for keeping enemy horse archers or other skirmishers at bay and capable of fighting other infantry in melee.

¬----------------

{trapeziatoi}
Trapezitai

{trapeziatoi_descr}
Alongside the infantry the Themata produces a reliable light cavalry as well known as Trapezitai. They are armed with spears and shields while protected only by medium armour. Trapezitai are primarily used as Prokoursatores (forerunners) - serving as the eyes and ears of an army on campaign. They are also cost effective and easy to keep in service, due to the nature of the Thematic system. Historically, Trapezitai often provided the field armies with a screen of light cavalry and often lured enemy forces into ambushes. Whithin their Thema they usually monitored and shadowed enemy incursions and performing hit & run  tactics against them.

{trapeziatoi_descr_short}
Light cavalry with strong charge. Good at chasing down archers and horse archers or flanking all but the heaviest of enemy units.

¬----------------

{tzakones}
Tzakones

{tzakones_descr}
The word tzakon, the origin of which is still uncertain, was used during the medieval Roman era in a number of distinct ways. It denoted a wide variety of military and paramilitary professions including light armed soldiers, fortress guards, palace guards as well as paramilitary police. Even an adequate supply of fleet-marines was provided by the Tzakones, supposed to man the vessels of the imperial navy. Armed with mace and shield they became a reliable and effective force.

{tzakones_descr_short}
Imperial marines, effective against light and medium infantry. Should avoid heavy cavalry. 

¬----------------

{varangian_guard}
Varangoi 

{varangian_guard_descr}
In the 10th century, the emperors of the 'new Rome' decided to hire an elite unit of foreign bodyguards, since their own were often prone to court intrigue and assassination. These guards became known as the Varangians and were originally formed by Kievan Rus. During its existence the guard often consisted of Norsemen, Rus, Germans and many Saxons from the island of Britain, so much so that, by the twelfth century, the Varangian Guard was sometimes referred to as 'the English Guard'. They were armoured with the finest mail, equipped with large axes and hurlbats, and were often the heavy infantry punch after an initial cavalry charge. They should be used as ultra-heavy infantry, as there aren't many enemies that can stand up to them properly. Historically, the Varangian guard provided a new Tagmata to make up for the hemhorraging of manpower in the others. While some of these recovered from their losses, the Varangians were already established in their place. They were also frighteningly good at what they did, guard the emperor and fight as his shock troops.

{varangian_guard_descr_short}
Disciplined and feared heavy infantry with high moral. Well suited for assaults and if supported by spearmen very reliable in holding a battle line. Very expensive and best used at facing the enemies heaviest infantry.

¬----------------

{thematic_cavalry}
Hippeis

{thematic_cavalry_descr}
Alongside the infantry the Themata produces a reliable medium cavalry as well, exemplified by these men. They are armed with spears and shields while protected only by medium armour. Hippeis are primarily a flanking cavalry and have a good aptitude for outfighting most equivalent cavalry. They are also cost effective and easy to keep in service, due to the nature of the Thematic system. Historically, Thematic Hippeis were often of this middle of the road sort. They produced a decent melee force supporting the heavier cavalry by charging in behind them, and providing a 'second shock' that often broke enemy armies after the initial charge. Being followed by waves of light and small groups of heavy infantry, these cavalrymen can make quite a dent in the melee.

{thematic_cavalry_descr_short}
Medium cavalry with powerful charge. Good suited in supporting heavier cavalry and for flanking manoeuvres.

¬----------------

{thematic_infantry}
Peltastai

{thematic_infantry_descr}
The system of the Themata has kept the Roman Empire safe for four hundred years against the Arabs to the east. The new Turkish enemy has strained the system to the breaking point. The cost effective and competent soldiers it produces might be lost forever if the system is not reorganized. These soldiers carry spears and shields and wear light armour. Despite this equipment, they are often steadfast and dependable soldiers, the product of their training and the ingenious system of the themes. They can be used as a medium infantry, even if their equipment is light. Historically, the Thematic infantry often proved themselves to be more robust and dependable than their Muslim counterparts. With the disolving of the veteran Armenian themes a few years before the Battle of Manzikert, forty thousand battle hardened soldiers were lost to the empire. Recovering this system will be a paramount concern to any serious Roman Emperor. 

{thematic_infantry_descr_short}
Medium spearmen, good suited for temporarily holding a battle line or reinforcing weak spots.

¬----------------

{trebizond_archers}
Trebizontai Toxotai

{trebizond_archers_descr}
The archers of the East Roman army are often trained in a particular way, by the archers of Trebizond. They carry composite bows and are among the finest archers in Christendom. They are able to fight in melee as light infantry as well as release a hail of arrows upon their enemies. Historically, Trebizond Archers are a near elite archer unit that carry long composite bows. They can often stop a cavalry charge dead, as happened many times against Kurdish and Berber cavalry. They were often the first line of defense against mounted archery as well, because they could fire farther. Using them in the historical manner is probably wisest, because they are among the most useful Roman troops. 

{trebizond_archers_descr_short}
Medium archers, suited well for keeping enemy horse archers or other skirmishers at bay and capable of fighting light infantry in melee.

¬----------------

{turcoman_archers}
Turcoman Tribal Foot Archers

{turcoman_archers_descr}
The Turcomans, from Turkmenistan and north-eastern Persia, are adept in desert warfare. They are primarily archers, but can fight as light infantry if they need to do so. They are best used to weaken an enemy for others to attack. Their combat abilities are best reserved for self defence.

{turcoman_archers_descr_short}
Light archers, capable of keeping enemy skirmishers at bay and fighting other light infantry.

¬----------------

{seljuk_horse_archers}
Turcoman Tribal Horse Archers

{seljuk_horse_archers_descr}
The Seljuks rely on its vast quantities of quite light horse archers, coming from several Steppe tribes. Mainly of Turcoman origin, lots of those bow-armed horsemen offer their services as mercenaries in a lot of regions, besides the Rus also for example different Saracen and Arab rulers hired them into their armies, and as well they are in service of Byzantine leaders and even this kind of warriors was adopted by the Siculo Normans latest as they got the upperhand on Sicily over the Arabs. They ride fast mounts capable of outrunning almost all other cavalry units.

{seljuk_horse_archers_descr_short}
Light bow-armed cavalry, best used for harassing slower and chasing routed enemies.

¬----------------

{szekely}
Hungarian Horse Archers

{szekely_descr}
Light cavalry from the fringes of Hungary, partially they are the famous Szekely's, but the vast of them are descendents of the Magyar tribes. These men are highly skilled mobile scouts and skirmishers, also capable for melee, though too lightly-equipped for real heavy combat, though they make ideal raiders, useful for disrupting enemy formations before an attack by heavier units.

{szekely_descr_short}
Bow-armed light cavalry, best used in harassing slower or chasing routed enemies, capable in fighting light infantry in melee.

¬----------------

{norman_cavalry}
Norman Cavalry

{norman_cavalry_descr}
Norman cavalry fight in what was the traditional way of the Frankish horsemen of the dark age with javelins and spears, paired with the typical Norman melee skills, sometimes charging right ahead into the enemy line, but better used to harass skirmishers or using gaps and flanks to break a line. However they one of the first units who professionally used the stirrup, which was commonly applied by knights for the charge attack.

{norman_cavalry_descr_short}
Heavy cavalry with powerful charge. These Norman horsemen use spears in battle, but are inferior to real knights and steady spearmen.

¬----------------

{siculo_greek_marines}
Siculo-Greek Sailors

{siculo_greek_marines_descr}
In fine Greek tradition, the Kingdom of Sicily fields a group of javelin wielding skirmishers, calling Grifones. These men are drawn from the Sicilian Greek population, only wearing a tunic, trousers, and helm. They carry a small shield, a few javelins, and a small axe. Their javelins bring a deadly sting, and since most armies no longer use the javelin (mainly due to lack of training in its use), the Grifones can bring a needed close support element to Sicilian arms. Historically, the Grifones were a throwback to the ancient Greek Akontistai. They were mainly Greek Orthodox Sicilians, but many became quite accomplished and they were all certainly valued by their Norman overlords. 

{siculo_greek_marines_descr_short}
Light infantry with short ranged missiles, excellent at harassing enemy skirmishers or luring enemy infantry into the battle. However they suffer from weak defence as well as low morale and should avoid cavalry at all cost.

¬----------------

{siculo_norman_guardsmen}
Siculo-Norman Guardsmen

{siculo_norman_guardsmen_descr}
Anyone can use a crossbow and a few weeks practice will make anyone a master of it - archers have to be trained for years if not for decades. Once trained as a crossbowman, even the humblest peasant can kill the mightiest knight. This weapon is often seen as 'unfair' - by the mighty and therefore its use against Christians is prohibited by the pope.

{siculo_norman_guardsmen_descr_short}
Armoured Crossbowmen as Guardsmen of the Sicilian Isle and their Nobles, capable also in melee combat.

¬----------------

{norman_knights}
Norman Knights

{norman_knights_descr}
The feudal knight originated from the old Carolingian cavalry of the Franks and eventually came to include the nobility of the kingdom, the landowning upper class. These men begin their training in infancy, they are able to buy their own armour, weapons and what seperates them from other soldiers, their own horse. In exchange for the land their king gives them, knights must answer to the king's call in case of war and must raise their own bodies of soldiers to fight under their command. In western European armies the feudal knight is the heavy cavalry arm of the fighting force, and a powerful asset for any commander to have. The Norman nobles learned very quick from the Frankish nobles how to fight on the horseback in the Frankish style. Together with their traditional warrior skills, they became one of the best knights. Sometimes more disciplined than their European pendant, and feared by every oponent. 

{norman_knights_descr_short}
Heavy cavalry with very powerful charge. Disciplined but ineffective at attacking heavy infantry head-on.

¬----------------

{frankish_cavalry}
Frankish Horsemen

{frankish_cavalry_descr}
These skilled Horsemen are the descendents of the Frankish mounted warriors of the dark age, not nobles, but proud and free mounted mercenaries, who eventually get a knight status in later times. They fight in what was the traditional way of the Frankish cavalrymen with javelins and spears, sometimes charging right ahead into the enemy line, but better used to harass skirmishers or using gaps and flanks to break a line. However they one of the first units who professionally used the stirrup, which was commonly applied by knights for the charge attack.

{frankish_cavalry_descr_short}
Medium cavalry with powerful charge. These Frankish horsemen use spears in battle, but are inferior to real knights and steady spearmen.

¬----------------

{mounted_nobles}
Danish Knights

{mounted_nobles_descr}
A high knight with his mounted nobles called upon from the numerous Jarls of the Danish nobility. They are well equipped and trained, just similar to european feudal knights. The combination of their mobility and their fighting skill makes them a very effective heavy cavalry, able to engage all kinds of opponents.

{mounted_nobles_descr_short}
Heavy cavalry with powerful charge, similar to other european knights.

¬----------------

{murabitin_bodyguard}
Murabitin Bodyguard

{murabitin_bodyguard_descr}
The tough Murabitin are recruited from the desolate Almohad provinces along the North African coast. They are honourable and brave, ready to fight and die at their leader's command. A Murabitin Bodyguard is armed with a lance and a sword, while wearing also good armour.

{murabitin_bodyguard_descr_short}
Excellent heavy cavalry with powerful charge and very good in melee. Ineffective at attacking heavy infantry head-on.

¬----------------

{high_naxarar}
Elite Naxarar Cavalry 

{high_naxarar_descr}
The Naxarar (lords) were the significant land owners of Armenia, like the feudal lords of Europe. They were administrators in peacetime and warriors in wartime, fighting as a well equipped heavy cavalry unit. Of course the highest nobility equipped themselves with these formidable warriors as bodyguards.

{high_naxarar_descr_short}
Excellent heavy cavalry with powerful charge and melee attack. Ineffective at attacking heavy infantry head-on.

¬----------------


{early_kings_cavalry_bg}
Household Knights  

{early_kings_cavalry_bg_descr}
These Feudal Knights have the honor to compagnon the local lords or even the high king as their personal household knights, and function as bodyguards. They are often from the royal family or other wealthy loyal retinues from the highest nobility. These knights are best equipped and armoured. Honourable, brave, ready to fight and die at their leader's command. Few men can match these highly trained and skilled nobles. Despite their loyal and brave status, they aren't always far better fighters than other knights. 

{early_kings_cavalry_bg_descr_short}
Excellent heavy cavalry with powerful charge, but can be occasionally ineffective in the close combat of settlements.

¬----------------

{ghulam_bodyguards}
Ghulam Bodyguards

{ghulam_bodyguards_descr}
Ghulam - the word means freed slave - cavalry are the best warriors available to the Sultan and form his bodyguard. In heavy mail and armed with lances, they are at least as good as other heavy cavalry. The Sultan (and every prince) leads Ghulams. Additional units can be trained at high costs.

{ghulam_bodyguards_descr_short}
Excellent heavy cavalry, disciplined and with powerful charge. Ineffective at attacking heavy infantry head-on.

¬----------------

{siculo_norman_nobles}
Siculo-Norman Nobles 

{siculo_norman_nobles_descr}
Siculo-Norman Nobles are often members of the royal family or other wealthy loyal retinues from the highest nobility. These knights are best equipped and armoured. Honourable, brave, ready to fight and die at their leader's command. Few men can match these highly trained and skilled nobles.

{siculo_norman_nobles_descr_short}
Excellent heavy cavalry with very powerful charge. Disciplined but ineffective at attacking heavy infantry head-on.

¬----------------

{cuman_heavy_cavalry}
Cuman Heavy Cavalry

{cuman_heavy_cavalry_descr}
The nomadic Turkic people, conquering what is present day southern Ukraine and Russia in the 11th century and founding a nomadic state in the steppes along the Black Sea were known as Kipchaks or Cumans (western Kipchaks). They invaded the territory of Moldavia, Wallachia and part of Transylvania in the 11th century, and from there they continued their plundering of the Byzantine Empire and the Kingdom of Hungary. They were famed for their heavy horsemen who armed themselves in heavy chain mail and lamellar armour, and wore distinctive helmets with face masks.

{cuman_heavy_cavalry_descr_short}
Excellent heavy cavalry with good charge, armed with bows and swords. They are disciplined and strong in hand-to-hand fights, nonetheless heavy spearmen still have to be treated with respect.

¬----------------

{mala_druzhina}
Mala Druzhina

{mala_druzhina_descr}
It was said: "The prince fights for glory, but the druzhina fights for the prince." Druzhina comes either from a Slavic terms meaning friendship or family. The Mala Druzhina or "Little Druzhina" were the personal bodyguards of Slavic princes. They are among the best fighters and use the best equipment available, making for an excellent heavy cavalry unit. Poland is moving away from the use of druzhina units, but their royal units are still an exception to this rule.

{mala_druzhina_descr_short}
Excellent heavy cavalry, disciplined and outclass most units in sheer strength but should avoid spearmen.

¬----------------

{knizeci_druzina}
Knizeci Druzina

{knizeci_druzina_descr}
Druzina comes either from Slavic terms meaning friendship or family. The Knizeci Druzhina were the personal bodyguards of the Bohemian King. They are among the best fighters, using the best available equipment consisting of chain mail armour, large shields, long spears and good swords.

{knizeci_druzina_descr_short}
Excellent heavy cavalry, disciplined and with powerful charge. Ineffective at attacking heavy infantry head-on.

¬----------------

{dogheads}
Dogheads

{dogheads_descr}
Psohlavci or dogheads, named after the heads of dogs they painted on their shields, were free residents of the Bohemian border lands, especially around the Domazlice region, whose highest priority was to defend the borders of the Bohemian Kingdom. That is why they were the recipients of special privileges, such as were unseen in those days. They didn’t have to pay taxes, could move freely, learn crafts or hunt and fish unrestricted in the borderland woods. Even in times of peace they were allowed to carry a weapon, which most of the time was an axe.

{dogheads_descr_short}
Impetuous light Infantry, good suited for setting ambushes in woods, not reliable in holding a battle line. Ineffective against cavalry and heavy or steady infantry.

¬----------------

{varlets_of_bohemia}
Varlets of Bohemia

{varlets_of_bohemia_descr}
In early middle ages, Bohemian lands were renowned for the bravery and cruelty of their armies, which often served in foreign lands on European battlefields. Bohemian rulers liked to call up criminals indicted with the death penalty to serve in their armies and redeem their freedom, if they show courage in especially difficult circumstances. They painted their faces with black clay and acted as though they were not of this world. It was rumored that before a battle they made figurines of little toddlers out of dough, which they later baked and ate to further unnerve their opponents.

{varlets_of_bohemia_descr_short}
Impetuous but balanced medium infantry. Good suited for reinforcing a battle line. Ineffective against cavalry.

¬----------------

{hueste}
Hueste

{hueste_descr}
Hueste - deduced vom hostis meaning host, army, troop and invented in Aragon - are another type of Iberian raid militia, used for offensive operations. Similar to the Fonsado, but less armoured and often using double handed axes. They are still militia, with lower moral than professionals, but superior to most other militias, levies and peasants in close combat.

{hueste_descr_short}
Light raider militia with fair moral. Superior to militia and levies, but weak against professional infantry and cavalry. Vulnerable to missiles.

¬----------------

{swabian_swordsmen}
Swabian Swordsmen

{swabian_swordsmen_descr}
The Swabians of south-western Germany are a tough people, regarded almost as a race apart by their fellow Germans. Armoured in mail and armed with great two-handed swords, Swabian swordsmen are a powerful and feared heavy infantry unit with the emphasis on attack!

{swabian_swordsmen_descr_short}
Feared heavy infantry with powerful charge. Reliable in holding a battle line if supported by spearmen and good for cutting a hole in opposing lines. Ineffective against heavy cavalry.

¬----------------

{thuringian_archers}
Thuringian Archers

{thuringian_archers_descr}
The archers of the Thuringian region are excellent bowmen pressed into service by many German lords and duchies.

{thuringian_archers_descr_short}
Light Infantry, good suited for ambushes, superior to levy archers in every way.

¬----------------

{viking_huscarls}
Viking Huscarls

{viking_huscarls_descr}
Huscarls are the loyal followers of a Viking Jarl, serving him as a bodyguard and personal staff in peacetime while fighting by his side in times of war. Being the professional and elite warriors in the Viking times that find its end already, they remained existent for the Scandinavian christianened rulers in some locations, and even some of the Huscarls are resistent versus the christianity. They are superior infantry who fear nearly nothing, more effective and expensive than the usual Carls (free men) who are called to fight only in wartimes.

{viking_huscarls_descr_short}
Heavy infantry with excellent morale. Good suited for assaults and capable of holding a battle line if supported by spearman.

¬----------------

{teutonic_mounted_sergeants}
Teutonic Mounted Sergeants

{teutonic_mounted_sergeants_descr}
The fighting Orders are socially exclusive, not taking men from the lower ranks of society into the Order itself. The Teutonic Sergeants are socially inferior men to the Order knights, though trained as heavy cavalry, but without the dash and valour of true knights. In battle, they are almost as effective as the Order knights.

{teutonic_mounted_sergeants_descr_short}
Medium cavalry with powerful charge. Good suited for flanking manoeuvres and dealing with light cavalry and infantry, especially archers.

¬----------------

{teutonic_foot_knights}
Teutonic Order Foot Knights

{teutonic_foot_knights_descr}
The Teutonic Knights are a German fighting order, committed to fight against heretics, infidels and pagans alike. They are easily the equals in combat of the other Orders of Knighthood, if not quite so disciplined. This 'lack' of discipline is of no comfort to those facing Teutonic Knights in battle! On foot these knights rely on the vigorous effect of their Longswords. They are best used during sieges or in extended wooded landscapes but otherwise are not cost effective and easy pickings for archers due to their lack of shields. These men are the Order Brothers of the Teutonic Order in the Levante or the baltic rooms, where these knights founded a state on their own.

{teutonic_foot_knights_descr_short}
Reliable heavy assault infantry with powerful charge, good suited for cutting a hole in the enemy battle line and during sieges. Ineffective against heavy cavalry. Vulnerable to archers.

¬----------------

{feudal_knights_jeru}
Kingdom of Jerusalem Knights  

{feudal_knights_jeru_descr}
Guard Knights of the Kingdom of Jerusalem. In most cases they are descendents of the first crusaders or european reinforcements, in any case nobles or lesser nobles, skilled in the same kind as their european pendants. They are reliable, excellent heavy cavalry, able to break many enemies when they charge.

{feudal_knights_jeru_descr_short}
Disciplined heavy cavalry with powerful charge. Eventually ineffective at attacking heavy infantry head-on.

¬----------------

{knights_of_santiago_early}
Knights of Santiago 

{knights_of_santiago_early_descr}
Originally guards for Christian pilgrims in Spain, the Knights of Santiago are an order of mixed character both military and hospitaller like the Knights of St. John, organised along semi-monastic lines. They are reliable, excellent heavy cavalry, able to break many enemies with their charge and are without the impetuous folly often shown by secular western knights.

{knights_of_santiago_early_descr_short}
Disciplined heavy cavalry with powerful charge. Ineffective at attacking heavy infantry head-on.

¬----------------

{algarave}
Algarave

{algarave_descr}
Algaraves are those who fight in the raids that were so common during the height of the Reconquista period. They are mounted on the fastest steeds available and almost unarmoured at all - this results in a very fast cavalry unit with good stamina, but somewhat fragile. Although unarmoured, they are very skilled in hand-to-hand combat and are ideal for driving away or destroying enemy horse archers or light cavalry. Historically, raids into Andalusia were very common during the Reconquista. These raids were known by different terms, such as a Correruda (deep penetrating raid) or an Algara (raids often carried out in conjunction with an attacking force). Algaraves were those men who fought in an Algara and are markedly different from other light cavalry in western Christian armies. Most of the Algaraves were actually knights themselves, out to loot for the material benefits and enrichment that plunder provides as well as the spritual benefits from fighting for the defense of Christendom against the infidel invaders. Furthermore for the political benefits of being seen as a great and effective warrior, certainly worth being given more privileges and honours by the King himself!

{algarave_descr_short}
Lightly armoured knights with powerful charge, excellent fighting skill and very fast movement speed. Best at hit-and-run attacks, but should avoid heavier cavalry and steady infantry.

¬----------------

