¬ ;AsPaladin / Last Change: July 30, 2006; Bugfix (typo) within 0.50 testphase/DaVinci


¬ ================= 1072 Early Era Below =================

{YEAR_LENGTH_TITLE}		Omar Khayyám Calculates the Length of a Year
{YEAR_LENGTH_BODY}		Omar Khayyám has calculated that a year has 365.242198 days in it.  This calculation is incredibly accurate and shows the degree to which Islamic science has surpassed all others.

{CELESTIAL_GLOBE_TITLE}		A Scientific Breakthrough!
{CELESTIAL_GLOBE_BODY}		Ibrahim al-Sahdi of Valencia has just built a 'celestial globe'.  This strange, bronze ball can be used to measure and track the heavens.  This one in particular has forty-seven different constellation engraved on it.  

{PALMYRA_DESTROYED_TITLE}	Palmyra Destroyed by Earthquake
{PALMYRA_DESTROYED_BODY}	The once great city of Palmyra has been destroyed by a massive earthquake.  For over a millennia the city was a stop along the caravan routes from China and it enjoyed great wealth. Now it is ruins.  

{ASSASSINS_TITLE}			A New Deadly Sect 
{ASSASSINS_BODY}			An Isamili sect leader, Hasan ibn al-Sabbah, has seized the mountain fortress of Alamut for the al-Da'wa al-Jadīda sect.  Know as the Hashashin by the locals this sect of fanatics, called the fedayeen, which are will kill and be killed for their leader.  It is rumored that the sect also offers its services for a price.  

{FIRST_CRUSADE_TITLE}		The First Crusade
{FIRST_CRUSADE_BODY}		The Council of Clermont has ended and Pope Urban II, at the urging of Emperor Alexius I Comnenus, has declared a holy war against the Muslims occupying the Holy Land. 

{CANTERBURY_LEP_TITLE}		A Rash of Leprosy in England
{CANTERBURY_LEP_BODY}		A recent outbreak of leprosy has afflicted the region of Kent to such an extent that numerous new leper-houses have been built.  The unfortunate victims have been ordered not enter inns, churches, mills, or bake houses, to touch healthy people or dine with them, to wash in the streams, or to walk in narrow footpaths.  The church has even taken the step to give these people a funeral Mass and symbolic burial.

{ONION_DOME_TITLE}		New Architecture Developed
{ONION_DOME_BODY}			Reports from Novgorod indicate that a new type of architecture has been pioneered.  On the Church of St. Nicholas the so called 'onion dome' has been fully realized.  This style is bound to spread among the Orthodox world and beyond.  

{BURNED_STAKE_TITLE}		A Heretic Burned!
{BURNED_STAKE_BODY}		The vile heretic Basil the Physician has been burned to death at the order of the Byzantine Emperor.  Let that be a warning to the Bogomil sect that he led. 

{LATERAN_COUNCIL1_TITLE}	The First Lateran Council
{LATERAN_COUNCIL1_BODY}		A great meeting of all of the Bishops and Archbishops of the West has ended.  The meeting has introduced many new canon laws.  These laws include provisions forbidding priests, deacons, sub deacons, and monks from marrying or taken concubines.  Also excommunication is now the punishment for any layman appropriating church offerings or fortifies a church.

{RELIGIONS_SECTS_BOOK_TITLE}	A Treatise on Religion
{RELIGIONS_SECTS_BOOK_BODY}	Muhammad al-Shahrastani, the Muslim scholar, has completed his 'Treatise on the Religious and Philosophical Sects'.  This book studies the histories and teachings of the religions of the world.  The book is remarkably unbiased and impartial, much more so than anything be written in Europe. 

{INTRO_CE_TITLE}	A New Epoche Evolves
{INTRO_CE_BODY}	Anno Domini 1099 - The Norman, Frankish and Latin nobility conquered the Holy Land. 'Deus lo Vult!' was the shout a few years ago at the Catholic Synode in Clermont. Between 1096 and 1099, first Edessa, then Antiochia and recently Jerusalem was taken by the multi-ethnic crusader army, led by barons and dukes. Balduin, brother of Godefroy de Bouillon, of Flemish noble houses, founded the Principlity of Edessa, the first crusader state. Principality of Antiochia, proclaimed as second crusader state under Boemundo di Taranto, a Siculo-Norman nobleman and adventurer. And finally, the Kingdom of Jerusalem, ruled by Godefroy de Bouillon, the holy city itself, recently under the realms of the Fatimids, but formerly subjugated under the Seljuk rule, who are at war with each other since the Great-Seljuk Sultan Malik Shah ruled Baghdad, who died a few years ago, this led the Grand Seljuk empire into a crisis. However, this crusade and these state foundations will change the world forever. Many crusaders went back home or are still on the way, and so the legends of chivalrous knights and its followers make its round at the courts and within the common folks. It is this, what is laying the basements for the knighthood's property of the so-called chivalry, whereas its high goals weren't always the reality! ... Now, how was it possible for the crusaders to take that important locations within 3 years, proclaiming new christian states in an environment of islamic ruled lands? The Muslims in Near-East, Egypt and Asia Minor are grossly disunited realms. The islamic main powers are the Grand-Seljuks, the Rum-Seljuks and the Fatimids. The Seljuk houses are followers of the Sunna, whereas the Fatimids are believers of the Shia. The other Muslims, namely the Arabic and Berber powers in north-african and iberian regions are as well divided a lot. There, the Zirid Berbers of Tunesia, once Vasalls of the Fatimids, made themselves independent, and call the Seljuk maintained Abassid center of Baghdad their allies, whereas the Mahgreb and Andalusian leaders are followers of the Shia party. Besides those main powers there are several independent mainly islamic states, just of different branches, sometimes Sunna or Shia followers. - A note for the player, if factions East-Franks/Germans or Norman-England played: Take care, some of your crusading knights are still in the Levante. 

{EARTHQUAKE_SYRIA_TITLE}	An Earthquake Rocks Aleppo
{EARTHQUAKE_SYRIA_BODY}		An earthquake has struck Aleppo and thousands are feared dead.  

{LATERAN_COUNCIL2_TITLE}	The Second Lateran Council
{LATERAN_COUNCIL2_BODY}		The Church has finished another great meeting, and new canon laws of been created.  Of note to the knights of Europe is the new law forbidding, on the pain of deprivation of a Catholic burial, of tournaments and joust that endanger life.

{THE_ALEXIAD_TITLE}		A History
{THE_ALEXIAD_BODY}		Princess Anna Comnena, daughter of Alexius I, has written 'The Alexiad'.  It is the history of the Byzantine Empire under her father. It covers both political events and military events including the First Crusade.

{THOMAS_BECKET_TITLE}		Thomas Becket Murdered
{THOMAS_BECKET_BODY}		Thomas Becket, the Archbishop of Canterbury, has been murder in Canterbury Cathedral.  As he was leading Vespers, four wicked knights working for the English King slew him.  The faithful across Europe have already declared him a martyr!        

{LATERAN_COUNCIL3_TITLE}	The Third Lateran Council
{LATERAN_COUNCIL3_BODY}		Another meeting of the Catholic Church has occurred and new canon law has been enacted.  One law decrees that only the cardinals shall have the privilege of electing the Pope.  It also forbids tournaments, organizes asylums for lepers, and calls on the princes to suppress heresy. Finally, the council calls for a prohibition on Christians supplying Muslims with ship building materials.

{FIRST_INQUISITION_TITLE}	The Episcopal Inquisition
{FIRST_INQUISITION_BODY}	The Episcopal Inquisition, the first of the Inquisitions, has been established to deal with all of the heretics in Catholic Europe.  Its main target is the Cathars in southern France.

{HANSEATIC_LEAGUE_TITLE}	The Hanseatic League has Opened in Novgorod
{HANSEATIC_LEAGUE_BODY}		The Hanseatic League, an alliance of traders, as opened a office in Novgorod.  This is bound to increase the League's monopoly over trade in the Baltic Sea, enriching all of the traders involved. 

{THE_GIRALDA_TITLE}		A Magnificent Minaret
{THE_GIRALDA_BODY}		The rulers of Sevilla have completed a masterpiece of architecture.  They have competed the Giralda an enormously tall Minaret, which is rumored to be the tallest building on earth.  The building is a composite of numerous cultures, including some Roman ruins.  The tower is served by many ramps, which are wide enough for the muezzin to ride his horse to the top of when going to call the Adhan. 

{GESTA_HUNGARORUM_TITLE}	A History of the Hungarians
{GESTA_HUNGARORUM_BODY}		An unknown author has written the 'Gesta Hungarorum'.  This work contains information on the ruling families of the Kingdom of Hungary and says that they all are descendants of the Arpad family.

{FRANSICAN_ORDER_TITLE}		A New Monastic Order   
{FRANSICAN_ORDER_BODY}		Francis of Assisi has established his first monastery near Assisi.  His new order, the Franciscans, has sworn itself to poverty, fasting, reciting the Divine Office, obedience, and more.      

{MAGNA_CARTA_TITLE}		The Magna Carta
{MAGNA_CARTA_BODY}		The nobility of England has forced the English King to sign a charter.  The charter deals with a rights of the English King.  The document came about from a disagreement between the King, the Pope, and the Barons.  One of the clauses guarantees the freedom of the English Church.

{LATERAN_COUNCIL4_TITLE}	The Fourth Lateran Council
{LATERAN_COUNCIL4_BODY}		The Pope has called for a meeting in Rome with the purpose to define the central dogmas of Roman Christianity.  Furthermore, the Council acknowledges the sacraments of the Eucharist and penance needed for salvation.  The council also asserts that the Pope's power over the Church and over the kings of Europe.    

{TORRE_DEL_ORO_TITLE}		A Grand Tower in Sevilla
{TORRE_DEL_ORO_BODY}		A magnificent addition to the fortifications of Sevilla, the 'Tower of the Gold' has been started.  This twelve-sided watchtower protects access to Sevilla from the Guadalquivir River by employing a chain to block the river.  Its name comes from the plans to cover its dome in golden tiles. 

{SAMARKAND_SACKED_TITLE}	Samarkand Sacked!
{SAMARKAND_SACKED_BODY}		The Persian city of Samarkand has been sacked.  The ancient city was destroyed by hordes from the East and very few have survived.  God willing this horde will turn back home, but you should prepare for the worst should they not. 

¬ ================= 1223 High Era? Below =================


{STORM_FROM_THE_EAST_TITLE} 	A Storm from the East
{STORM_FROM_THE_EAST_BODY}	An endless horde of Mongol warriors has stormed out of the endless steppes and has invaded first lands of the Rus principalities.  Nobody knows their final destination, but all should prepare to face the Mongol's terrible wraith.  

{GUNPOWDER_FORMULA_TITLE}	Gunpowder
{GUNPOWDER_FORMULA_BODY}	Roger Bacon has written his 'On Marvelous Power of Art and Nature' describing formula for gunpowder. Although this knowledge has been know among the Arabs for some time.


{LAST_TEMPLARS_TITLE}		End of the Templars
{LAST_TEMPLARS_BODY}		On Friday October 13, 1307 the Knights Templar, having lost their foothold in the Middle East, is arrested in France by Phillip the Fair. They are disbanded on accusations of heresy, which they confirmed under torture. 7 years later Pope Clement V would secretly pardon them.  This event may be the cause of the idea that Friday 13th is an unlucky day.

{DIVINE_COMEDY_TITLE}		The Divine Comedy
{DIVINE_COMEDY_BODY}		By 1321 Dante had completed his masterpiece 'The Divine Comedy'. It traces his literary passage through Hell, Purgatory, and Heaven. It is also considered the last great piece of Medieval literature.



¬ ================= 1223 High Era? Below =================

{BLACK_DEATH1_TITLE} 		The Black Death
{BLACK_DEATH1_BODY}		In October 1347, on the back of Genovese traders, the dreaded Black Death came to Europe. The ensuing plague would kill roughly one third of Europe's population. The plague was not limited to Europe and total some 75 million people around the world would die.



¬ Not In Order Below

{SUMMA_THEOLOGICA_TITLE}	The Summa Theologica
{SUMMA_THEOLOGICA _BODY}	Thomas Acquinas has completed the 'Summa Theologica'.  This work, while not apologetic in nature, does contain a summary of the Catholic Faith.  It also contains the 'Quinquae viae' or 'Five Ways', which are philosophical proofs for the existence of God. 

{MONGOL_CHINA_TITLE}		A War in the Far East
{MONGOL_CHINA_BODY}		Traders from the Far East bring reports of a massive war.  The details are sketchy but millions are reported dead.  We should not worry yet, but we should continue to listen to reports from he East.

{FLOOD_HOLLAND_TITLE}		A Flood in Europe
{FLOOD_HOLLAND_BODY}		A massive flood has struck Friesland and the area is in ruins.  Up to 100,000 are believed dead.

{NO_ALLY_TITLE}			A Warning from the Pope
{NO_ALLY_BODY}			The Pope has forbidden all the followers of Christ from allying with the Mongol hordes.  Makes this matter all the stranger is that the Mongols have offered to help the Crusaders against the Muslims powers.     
