¬ Localisation file for transition screen quotes
¬ Lines in brackets are not to be translated

{Quote_1}
No free man shall be taken or imprisoned or dispossessed, or outlawed or exiled, or in any way destroyed, nor will we go upon him, nor will we send against him except by the lawful judgement of his peers or by the law of the land
{Quote_2}
In order for a war to be just, three things are necessary. First, the authority of the sovereign... Secondly, a just cause... Thirdly, a rightful intention
{Quote_3}
Because of the diverse conditions of humans, it happens that some acts are virtuous to some people, as appropriate and suitable to them, while the same acts are immoral for others, as inappropriate to them
{Quote_4}
That Emperour hath bid them sound their horns. The Franks dismount, and dress themselves for war, Put hauberks on, helmets and golden swords; Fine shields they have, and spears of length and force
{Quote_5}
Our men are very proud, No man on earth has more nor better found. In Chronicles of Franks is written down, What vassalage he had, our Emperour
{Quote_6}
My lords barons, Charles left us here for this; He is our King, well may we die for him: To Christendom good service offering
{Quote_7}
Science is nothing but perception
{Quote_8}
Will no one revenge me of the injuries I have sustained from one turbulent priest?
{Quote_9}
A latin knight, as long as his horse was in good condition, could not be knocked down. Covered by a mail hauberk from head to foot... the most violent blows had no effect on him. But once his horse was killed, the knight was thrown and taken prisoner
{Quote_10}
The Turks crept up, howling loudly and shooting a shower of arrows. Stunned and almost dead, and with many wounded, we immediately fled. And it was no wonder, for such warfare was new to us all
{Quote_11}
God would not have chosen Palestine if he had seen my Kingdom of Sicily
{Quote_12}
Philosophy is the highest music
{Quote_13}
Attention to health is life's greatest hindrance
{Quote_14}
Because of the feebleness of the human nature, and the pass of time, the old things fall into oblivion, we should strengthen the agreements of the contracting parties with the power of writing
{Quote_15}
Those good properties are called virtue what are given in the human nature. It is called virtus in latin, and there are four main virtues among all of the virtues: wisdom, bravery, temperateness and truth
{Quote_16}
Those who attacked believers in a prohibited way, now go to a war against the pagans, which is worthy to begin, and will be victorious. Let they be knights who used to be robers
{Quote_17}
Kill them all! God will know his own!
{Quote_18}
I am going on this journey to exalt the faith that you have given us and to bring down and destroy those who do not believe in you
{Quote_19}
I am the Flail of God. If you had not committed great sins, God would not have sent a punishment like me upon you
{Quote_20}
He is a fool who cannot be angry; but he is a wise man who will not
{Quote_21}
Had I been present at the Creation, I would have given some useful hints for the better ordering of the universe
{Quote_22}
And those people should not be listened to who keep saying the voice of the people is the voice of God, since the riotousness of the crowd is always very close to madness
{Quote_23}
If you are at Rome live in the Roman style; if you are elsewhere live as they live elsewhere
{Quote_24}
While the Franks - God damn them! - were conquering... the rulers and armies of Islam were fighting among themselves...
{Quote_25}
For when they saw those high ramparts and the strong towers... and the splendid palaces and soaring churches... they never thought there could be so rich and powerful a place on Earth
{Quote_26}
You took the Cross upon your shoulders; and on that Cross and on the Holy Gospels you swore that you would pass over Christian lands without violence... Far from carrying the Cross, you profane it and trample it underfoot
{Quote_27}
The People of Antioch were by no means pleased by the arrival of the Emperor. But when they saw it was not in their power to prevent him they came before him like slaves...
{Quote_29}
Nothing in the affairs of men is worthy of great anxiety
{Quote_30}
They assembled from all sides, one after another, with arms and horses and all the panoply of war... Like tributaries joining a river, they streamed from all directions towards us
{Quote_31}
We are all aware, as we have learnt from our elders before us, that Antioch was part of the Empire of Constantinople... Should we then deny the truth and oppose what we know to be right?
{Quote_32}
As for the size of Saladins army which would render you a coward that is just more fuel for Satan's eternal fire
{Quote_33}
No mercy for you, I shall take the city with all brutality known to your people and it shall run red in your blood until there is no blood left to run
{Quote_34}
We shall burn down all in the city, we will burn our holy places and our treasure, we shall kill our women and then we shall advance on you, and either it will be a great Frankish victory or we shall die honorably and leave you nothing but rubble
{Quote_35}
If a King were to be captured and his knights did nothing to help him be released, or merely sent money without fighting for it themselves then that King would deem them traitors, it is the same with God
{Quote_36}
First into battle and last out
{Quote_37}
It is the custom of Kings that one may do as one wishes in their own lands, you do as you will in your lands I will do as I will in mine
{Quote_38}
My Lords I can do no more for I am dead
{Quote_39}
I will accept the office, but no crown must be put on my head and I must never be called King. I cannot wear a crown of gold where Christ wore one of thorns nor will I be called King in the land where once lived the King of Kings
{Quote_40}
Spiritual chivalry means to restrain yourself from causing trouble while giving freely
{Quote_41}
A Sufi was asked, "What is spiritual chivalry ?". He said, "That it makes not difference whether a saint or an unbeliever is eating with you"
{Quote_42}
Behind you is the sea, before you, the enemy
{Quote_43}
I love war because of the victory in the end
{Quote_44}
Never make a defense or an apology until you are accused
{Quote_45}
77 chickens and 77 geese means nothing...
{Quote_46}
The beginning is the most important part of the work
{Quote_47}
A mathematician is a blind man in a dark room looking for a black cat which isn't there
{Quote_48}
The darkest places in hell are reserved for those who maintain their neutrality in times of moral crisis
{Quote_49}
Thus the day came for the Franks when the same of capture, defeat and disaster engulfed them
{Quote_50}
I have offered myself for sale, and He has bought me. By God, I neither agreed nor asked that the contract should be annulled!
{Quote_51}
We have mingled blood with flowing tears, and there is no room left in us for pity
{Quote_52}
It is not so much a difference of dogma that turns the hearts of the Greeks against you as the hatred of the Latins which has entered into their spirits...
{Quote_53}
Let us advance, and save the country and rescue the bold damsel in the tower
{Quote_54}
I will not wear a crown of gold where my Saviour wore one of thorns
{Quote_55}
The essence of futuwwa — noble, generous, and honorable conduct is that the servant should always be working for the sake of something other than himself
{Quote_56}
The spiritual warrior is he who has no enemy
{Quote_57}
Spiritual chivalry means that native and foreigner are the same to you
{Quote_58}
It is right to give every man his due
{Quote_59}
Democracy passes into despotism
{Quote_60}
If a man neglects education, he walks lame to the end of his life
{Quote_61}
If a man be endowed with a generous mind, this is the best kind of nobility
{Quote_62}
The knowledge of which geometry aims is the knowledge of the eternal
{Quote_63}
No law or ordinance is mightier than understanding
{Quote_64}
The soul of man is immortal and imperishable
{Quote_65}
Necessity, who is the mother of invention
{Quote_66}
All proofs rest on premises
{Quote_67}
We cannot learn without pain
{Quote_68}
He overcomes a stout enemy who overcomes his own anger
{Quote_69}
A great city is not to be confounded with a populous one
{Quote_70}
A good style must have an air of novelty, at the same time concealing its art
{Quote_71}
If some among them are innocent, it is expedient that they should be assayed like gold in the furnace and purged by proper judicial examination
{Quote_72}
Lord, do not believe the advice of the count. For he is a traitor, and you well know that he has no love for you, and wishes you to be ashamed, and that you should lose your Kingdom 
{Quote_73}
After Jerusaleum had been captured, saladin had the cross taken down from the Temple of the Lord, beating it with clubs, and had it carried on display for two days throughout the city
{Quote_74}
If you do not leave this pasturage, Saladin will come and attack you here. And if you retreat from this attack the shame and reproach will be very great
{Quote_75}
He ordered that all Hospitallers and Templars prisoners to be beheaded, choosing to have them dead rather than in prison
{Quote_76}
People of Valencia! I bring you bread!
{Quote_77}
A yeman hadde he and servantz namo. At that tyme, for hym liste ride so, And he was clad in cote and hood of grene
{Author_1}
The Magna Carta
{Author_2}
Saint Thomas Aquinas
{Author_3}
Saint Thomas Aquinas
{Author_4}
La Chanson de Roland
{Author_5}
Archbishop Turpin
{Author_6}
Archbishop Turpin
{Author_7}
Plato
{Author_8}
King Henry II of England speaking of Thomas Becket
{Author_9}
Baha Al Din, Saladin's biographer
{Author_10}
Gesta Francorum
{Author_11}
Frederick II of Hohenstaufen
{Author_12}
Plato
{Author_13}
Plato
{Author_14}
Béla III, King of Hungary in 1181 AD
{Author_15}
Alfonso X the Wise, King of Castille, 1221-1284 AD
{Author_16}
Foucher de Chartes - Gesta Francorum 1209 AD, quoting Urban II
{Author_17}
Abbott Arnaud-Amaury, emissary of Pope Innoncent III, during the Albigenser crusades
{Author_18}
Jaime I of Aragon
{Author_19}
Genghis Khan
{Author_20}
Plato
{Author_21}
Alfonso X the Wise, King of Castille, 1221-1284 AD
{Author_22}
Albinus Flaccus Alcuinus, 732-804, in a letter to Charlemagne
{Author_23}
Saint Ambrose, 340–397
{Author_24}
Ibn Al-Athir on the discord among the Muslim states
{Author_25}
Geoffrey of Villehardouin on the Latin's first sighting of Constantinople
{Author_26}
Nicetas Choniates on the Crusader passage through Byzantium
{Author_27}
Nicetas Choniates on the Emperor Manuel Komnenos' reception at Antioch
{Author_29}
Plato
{Author_30}
Anna Komnenos, The Alexiad on the arrival of the first Crusaders
{Author_31}
Fulk of Anjou, King of Jerusalem on the surrender of Antioch to the Emperor John Comnenus
{Author_32}
Reynald de Chattalion
{Author_33}
Saladin to Balien of Ibelin 
{Author_34}
Balien of Ibelin to Saladin during the Siege of Jerusalem
{Author_35}
Pope Innocent III
{Author_36}
war cry of the Knights Templar
{Author_37}
Reynald de Chatallion
{Author_38}
Grand Master of the Templar during the last fall of Acre
{Author_39}
Godfrey of Bouillon on being King of Jerusalem
{Author_40}
Junyad
{Author_41}
Sufi Tradition
{Author_42}
Tariq ibn-Ziyad 
{Author_43}
Sultan Alp Arslan of the Seljuk Turks
{Author_44}
King Charles I of England 
{Author_45}
Valdemar Atterdag of Denmark speaking of the Hanseatic declaration of war
{Author_46}
Plato
{Author_47}
Charles I of Hungary
{Author_48}
Dante Alighieri
{Author_49}
Unknown author, poem in praise of Nur ad-Din's campaigns against the Franks
{Author_50}
Hujjat ad-Din Yusuf Ibn Dibas Al-Findalawi, an elderly lawyer of Damascus, marching in his cities defence
{Author_51}
Abu l-Muzaffar al-Abiwardi - on the Frankish conquests in Syria
{Author_52}
Barlaam of Calabria in a letter to Pope Benedict XII
{Author_53}
A common knight to Guy de Lusignan urging him to go to battle with Saladin.
{Author_54}
Godfrey of Bouillon on being King of Jerusalem
{Author_55}
Abu 'l-Qasim al-Qushayri
{Author_56}
Abu Bakr al-Warraq
{Author_57}
Muhammad ibn Ali al-Tirmidihi
{Author_58}
Plato
{Author_59}
Plato
{Author_60}
Plato
{Author_61}
Plato
{Author_62}
Plato
{Author_63}
Plato
{Author_64}
Plato
{Author_65}
Plato
{Author_66}
Aristotle 
{Author_67}
Aristotle 
{Author_68}
Aristotle 
{Author_69}
Aristotle 
{Author_70}
Aristotle 
{Author_71}
Royal letter opening the enquiry into the Templars in 1307 AD
{Author_72}
Gerard of Ridefort to King Guy, 4th of July 1186 AD
{Author_73}
Terricus, acting commander of the Templars to Henry II in 1188 AD
{Author_74}
Gerard of Ridefort to King Guy, 4th of July 1186
{Author_75}
Imad Al-Din, Secretary and Chancellor to Saladin, 17th of May 1187 AD
{Author_76}
El cid Rodrigo Díaz de Vivar
{Author_77}
Geoffrey Chaucer, British poet 1340-1400 AD
{quote_78}
Be kind, for everyone you meet is fighting a harder battle
{quoted_79}
Plato
{quote_80}
Honi soit qui mal y pense
{trans_81}
Shame upon him who thinks evil of it
{quoted_82}
King Edward the Third, Motto of the Order of the Garter
{quote_83}
Deus Vult
{trans_84}
God wills it
{quoted_85}
Battle cry of the Crusaders
{quote_86}
O, God! You know that I have known You through what I have tried. Forgive me for making learning about You my way to reach You
{quoted_87}
Omar El Khayam
{quote_88}
What a student owes to the teacher is to be recipient to his teaching. The treasure of the teacher is knowledge which he reveals if the student receives it well
{quoted_89}
Ibn Hayan
{quote_90}
I agree or disagree until the student comes up with the answer by reason, logic, evidence and proof
{quoted_91}
Al Kindy
{quote_92}
Beauty of style and harmony and grace and good rhythm depend on simplicity 
{quoted_93}
Plato
{quote_94}
A true scientist is the one who adds one brick to the lofty edifice of science
{quoted_95}
Al Buhgdady
{quote_96}
Ubi Petris, ibi ergo ecclesia
{trans_97}
Where Peter is, there must be the Church
{quoted_98}
Saint Ambrose
{quote_99}
Non nobis Domine, non nobis, sed nomine tuo, da gloriam
{trans_100}
Not unto us Lord, not unto us, but to thy name give glory
{quoted_101}
Saint Bernard of Clairvaux
{quote_102}
A short life full of knowledge, joy and work is better than a long life empty of these pleasures at the end of which one walks on three limbs
{quoted_103}
Ibn Sina
{quote_104}
A learned man should not keep knowledge to himself and not write in a book before he faces God`s countenance
{quoted_105}
Ibn Sina
{quote_106}
The best way of teaching is to motivate my student over an issue and give him freedom to ask, and stimulate him until he reaches the answer by himself
{quoted_107}
Al Kindy
{quote_108}
"Indoctrination" is the worst of all methods of teaching
{quoted_109}
Al Kindy
{quote_110}
A man respects another for what he has of knowledge and science
{quoted_111}
Al Antaki
{quote_112}
You must keep sceptical of yourself and do not trust yourself all the way
{quoted_113}
Al Buhgdady
{quote_114}
You must check your thoughts against those of the scientists and their classifications
{quoted_115}
Al Buhgdady
{quote_116}
A human being is human by nature even if he knows not
{quoted_117}
Al Antaki
{quote_118}
Quar nous navons volu ne volons le Temple mettre en aucune servitute se non tant come il hy affiert
{trans_119}
For we did not and do not wish the Temple to be placed in any servitude except that which is fitting
{quoted_120}
Jacques de Molay, Grandmaster of the Knights Templar
{quote_121}
Tenir haut la Croix, donc je peux le voir par les flammes
{trans_122}
Hold the Cross high, so I may see it through the flames
{quoted_123}
Jeanne d'Arc
{quote_124}
Never could you bring a greater sacrifice before God as you do when you persecute those who rail against him
{quoted_125}
Paschalis II to Robert of Flanders
{quote_126}
A fair request should be followed by the deed in silence
{quoted_127}
Dante Alighieri
{quote_128}
Men acquire a particular quality by constantly acting in a particular way
{quoted_129}
Aristotle 
{quote_130}
The rulers of the states are the only ones who should have the privilege of lying
{quoted_131}
Plato
{quote_132}
Vous souhaitez voir; écouter. L'audience est une étape vers la vision
{trans_133}
You wish to see; listen. Hearing is a step towards vision
{quoted_134}
Saint Bernard of Clairvaux 
{quote_135}
I count him braver who overcomes his desires than him who overcomes his enemies; for the hardest victory is over self
{quoted_136}
Aristotle
{quote_137}
Philosophy is the science which considers truth
{quoted_138}
Aristotle
{quote_139}
Hope is a waking dream
{quoted_140}
Aristotle
{quote_141}
Qui m'aime me suive
{trans_142}
He who loves me, follows me
{quoted_143}
Philippe VI, de Valois in 1328 AD
{quote_144}
Concerning the women in the tents of the enemy, the Franks did nothing terrible to them rather they simply pierced their stomachs with lances
{quoted_145}
Fulcher of Chartes, after the victory near Antioch in July 1098 AD
{quote_146}
Ancient laws remain in force long after the people have the power to change them
{quoted_147}
Aristotle
{quote_148}
être humble quand vous êtes loué est une grand et rare réalisation
{trans_149}
To be humble when you are praised is a great and rare achievement
{quoted_150}
Saint Bernard of Clairvaux 
{quote_151}
Consider pleasures as they depart, not as they come
{quoted_152}
Aristotle
{quote_153}
How are the mighty fallen in the midst of battle!
{quoted_154}
II Samuel, I, 25
{quote_155}
The walls shall shake at the noise of the horsemen, and of the wheels, and of the chariots
{quoted_156}
Ezekiel, XXVI, 10
{quote_157}
Come del morire
{trans_158}
As sure as death
{quoted_159}
Il Filostrato by Giovanni Boccaccio
{quote_160}
He who will not when he may, may not when he will
{quoted_161}
John of Salisbury
{quote_162}
Je ne sais pas si vous êtes mon juge, mais fait attention pour ne pas juger mauvaisment, de peur que vous vous placez dans le grand danger
{trans_163}
I don't know if you are my judge, but take care not to judge wrongly, lest you place yourself in great danger
{quoted_164}
Jeanne d'Arc
{quote_165}
Dignity consists not in possessing honors, but in the consciousness that we deserve them
{quoted_166}
Aristotle 
{quote_167}
March divided and fight concentrated
{quoted_168}
Military maxim
{quote_169}
Divide and conquer
{quoted_170}
Military maxim
{quote_171}
Que je sais de la science divine et d'Ecritures Saintes, j'ai appris dans les bois et les champs
{trans_172}
What I know of the divine science and Holy Scriptures, I learnt in the woods and fields
{quoted_173}
Saint Bernard of Clairvaux  
{quote_174}
Oh la Guerre! Détesté par tout qui méprise l'injustice et le plus terrible pour n'importe qui qui il doit observer
{trans_175}
Oh War! Hated by all who despise injustice and most terrible for anyone who must witness it
{quoted_176}
Fulcher of Chartes after the Battle of Ramla in 1101 AD
{quote_177}
Education is an ornament in prosperity and a refuge in adversity
{quoted_178}
Aristotle
{quote_179}
Sachez que vous n'aurez ni gouvernement ni évêchés si vous n'êtes pas plus instruits que les autres
{trans_180}
Know that you will neither have government nor dioceses if you are not more informed than the others
{quoted_181}
Charlmagne
{quote_182}
A wise man among the ignorant is as a beautiful girl in the company of blind men
{quoted_183}
Saadi, a persian writer, 1184-1283 AD
{quote_184}
Seven women together may scarcely find one man to lay hold on, so many widows are there whose husbands are still living
{quoted_185}
Saint Bernhard of Clairvaux
{quote_186}
Nor do I seek to understand that I may believe, but I believe that I may understand. For this too I believe, that unless I first believe, I shall not understand
{quoted_187}
Saint Anselm of Canterbury 
{quote_188}
Blessed are the peacemakers, for they will be called sons of God
{quoted_189}
Matthew, V, 9
{quote_190}
The darkest places in hell are reserved for those who maintain their neutrality in times of moral crisis
{quoted_191}
Dante Alighieri
{quote_192}
Les chrétiens cherchent la renommée dans tuer de païens parce que Christ est honoré par cet acte
{trans_193}
Christians seek fame in killing heathens because Christ is honoured by this act
{quoted_194}
Saint Bernhard of Clairvaux
{quote_195}
L'esperienza de questa dolce vita
{trans_196}
The experience of this sweet life
{quoted_197}
Dante Alighieri
{quote_198}
Love is blind
{quoted_199}
Dante Alighieri
{quote_200}
It is better to be this unlearned woman, loving God with all her heart, than the most learned theologian lacking love. 
{quoted_201}
Saint Thomas Aquinas
{quote_202}
Who will free me from this turbulent priest?
{quoted_203}
King Henry II
{quote_204}
The banners of the King advance, the mystery of the cross shines bright, where his life went through with death, and from death brought forth life
{quoted_205}
Venantius Fortunatus in Analecta Hymnica in 600 AD
{quote_206}
And whan a beest is deed he hath no peyne; But man after his deeth moot wepe and pleyne
{quoted_207}
Geoffrey Chaucer in The Canterbury Tales
{quote_208}
To no man will we sell, or deny, or delay, right or justice.
{quoted_209}
The Magna Carta
{quote_210}
Faith has to do with things that are not seen and hope with things that are not at hand
{quoted_211}
Saint Thomas Aquinas
{quote_212}
Reason in man is rather like God in the world
{quoted_213}
Saint Thomas Aquinas
{quote_214}
The greatest happiness is to scatter your enemy and drive him before you, to see his cities reduced to ashes, to see those who love him shrouded and in tears.
{quoted_215}
Genghis Khan
{quote_216}
It is not sufficient that I succeed, all others must fail
{quoted_217}
Genghis Khan
{quote_218}
But above all things I strive to train them to be useful to the Holy Church of God and for the glory of your Kingdom
{quoted_219}
Albinus Flaccus Alcuinus in a letter to Charlemagne in 800 AD
{quote_220}
Nor should we listen to those who say "The voice of the people is the voice of god, for the turbulence of the mob is always close to insanity"
{quoted_221}
Albinus Flaccus Alcuinus in a letter to Charlemagne in 800 AD
{quote_222}
The energy of the mind is the essence of life
{quoted_223}
Aristotle 
{quote_224}
I love to doubt as well as know
{quoted_225}
Dante Alighieri
{quote_226}
Heat cannot be separated from fire, or beauty from the eternal
{quoted_227}
Dante Alighieri

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 29/03/2004 17:30:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 21/04/2004 17:30:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 13/05/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 03/06/2004 16:48:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 17/06/2004 13:01:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

{Author_63}
Plato

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*		This particular divider does not denote a changes round.
¬*	This is when the files were locked to be sent for Russian and Polish translation.
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 01/07/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 07/07/2004 17:15:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 15/07/2004 17:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 22/07/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 29/07/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 05/08/2004 12:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 12/08/2004 09:53:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 19/08/2004 16:05:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 01/09/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 03/09/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			EXPANSION PACK TEXT BEGINS HERE!!!
¬*		ALL TEXT BELOW THIS LINE SHOULD BE EXPANSION ADDITIONS/CHANGES ONLY!!!
¬*
¬*¬***** Changes made after 05/01/2005 15:18:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++